<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The poor widows mite, cast into the Lord's treasury wherein are contained some reasons in the justification of the meetings of the people of God called Quakers with an approbation of several truths held by them, and the ground of dark persecution discussed / written by a woman of the south, who came from the ends of the earth to hear the wisdom of him that is greater than Solomon, and doth a far off behold the happy estate of his friends and servants who stand continually before him, to hear and receive wisdom from him, who is the true Emanuel, now left it should be counted a libel or any should think we dare for own it in the world, I have subscribed my name.</title>
            <author>Hincks, Elizabeth.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1671</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 140 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 24 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2013-12">2013-12 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A43847</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing H2050</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R20070</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12443464</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 12443464</idno>
            <idno type="VID">62159</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A43847)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 62159)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 942:15)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The poor widows mite, cast into the Lord's treasury wherein are contained some reasons in the justification of the meetings of the people of God called Quakers with an approbation of several truths held by them, and the ground of dark persecution discussed / written by a woman of the south, who came from the ends of the earth to hear the wisdom of him that is greater than Solomon, and doth a far off behold the happy estate of his friends and servants who stand continually before him, to hear and receive wisdom from him, who is the true Emanuel, now left it should be counted a libel or any should think we dare for own it in the world, I have subscribed my name.</title>
                  <author>Hincks, Elizabeth.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>3-6, [2], 7-47 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.],</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London? :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1671.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
                  <note>Caption title: The widows suite, to her friend T.S. ...</note>
                  <note>Attributed to Elizabeth Hincks. cf. BM.</note>
                  <note>In verse.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Society of Friends --  England.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-06</date>
            <label>John Latta</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2013-02</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:62159:3"/>
            <p>THE POOR Widows Mite, Caſt into the LORD'S TREASURY. Wherein are contained Some Reaſons in the Juſtification of the Meetings of the People of God called <hi>QUAKERS</hi> with an Approbation of ſeveral <hi>Truths</hi> held by them, and the ground of <hi>Dark Perſecution</hi> Diſcuſſed.</p>
            <p>Written by a <hi>Woman</hi> of the <hi>South,</hi> who came from the ends of the Earth to hear the Wiſdom of him that is greater than <hi>Solomon,</hi> and doth a far off behold the happy Eſtate of his Friends and Servants who ſtand continually before him, to hear and receive Wiſdom from him; who is the true <hi>Emanuel.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Now leſt it ſhould be counted a <hi>Libel,</hi> or any ſhould think we dare not own it in the World, I have ſubſcribed my Name.</p>
            <q>
               <l>A MITE, if ALL, is more than ALL,</l>
               <l>Than they Abundance have,</l>
               <l>That have not FAITH to give up ALL,</l>
               <l>Their ALL will not them Save.</l>
            </q>
            <p>Printed for the uſe and benefit of ſuch <hi>Bees</hi> as ſuck their <hi>Hony</hi> from the <hi>Flowers</hi> and <hi>Bloſſoms</hi> that God makes to ſpring; that they may have to keep <hi>themſelves alive</hi> in the <hi>dark ſtormy Winter, 1671</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="dedication">
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:62159:1"/>
            <head>THE Widows Suite TO Her FRIEND <hi>T. S.</hi> whom ſhe deſires to be <hi>IMPRIMATOR</hi> to her Small Mite.</head>
            <opener>
               <salute>My Friend,</salute>
            </opener>
            <l>THeſe Lines to thee are ſent that thou mayst them review,</l>
            <l>Becauſe I know thou doſt Believe and Seeſt in things are True.</l>
            <l>So that if ought be Unſav'ry, and thou dost know the Fault,</l>
            <l>Thou having in thy Houſe Seas'ning, put thereto the <hi>Earths Salt.</hi>
            </l>
            <l>Moreover I not willing am, that <hi>Truth</hi> at all be Blam'd,</l>
            <l>Nor would I do or give out ought that any ſhould be ſham'd.</l>
            <pb n="4" facs="tcp:62159:2"/>
            <l> Therefore unto the <hi>Sanctu'ry</hi> I do my <hi>Weights</hi> forth bring</l>
            <l>The <hi>Ballance</hi> thereof them to <hi>try,</hi> this is the only thing.</l>
            <l>To have all right and made good weight, <hi>Infirmities</hi> to heal,</l>
            <l>And what <hi>Weights</hi> equal are and juſt, on them to ſtrike the <hi>Seal.</hi>
            </l>
            <l>Which when they have <hi>Truths Seal</hi> on them Oh! then none will question:</l>
            <l>Let the Noble <hi>Bereans</hi> ſearch, they'l find the <hi>Weights</hi> all one.</l>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="poems">
            <pb n="5" facs="tcp:62159:2"/>
            <head>The Poor WIDOWS MITE Caſt into the LORDS TREASURY.</head>
            <head type="sub">Where in are contained in ſhort, ſome reaſons in the Juſtification of the Meetings of the People of God called QUAKERS, <hi>&amp;c.</hi>
            </head>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">N</seg>O <hi>Prologue, Preface, Frontiſpice,</hi> nor no <hi>Epiſtle</hi> have,</l>
               <l>To Uſher in this little <hi>Mite,</hi> that long hath lain in <hi>Grave.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But now a <hi>Reſurrection</hi> hath, and from the <hi>Grave is come,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And in the <hi>Holy City</hi> walks, though before <hi>deaf</hi> and <hi>dumbe.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Nor did it <hi>ſee</hi> at all, for that, in's very <hi>Birth</hi> 'twas <hi>blind,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Nor <hi>taſte</hi> the <hi>goodneſs</hi> of his God, nor could him <hi>feel</hi> or <hi>find.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Now <hi>Praiſes, praiſes</hi> unto him, that <hi>quickned</hi> hath <hi>dry Bones,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>By <hi>breathing</hi> makes the ſences <hi>live,</hi> to <hi>Abraham's</hi> Seed of Stones.</l>
               <l>This is the mighty <hi>Power</hi> of <hi>God,</hi> on us that <hi>blind</hi> were <hi>born,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>His giving forth his <hi>Light,</hi> his <hi>Chriſt,</hi> his <hi>Everlaſting <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>orn</hi>
               </l>
               <l>His <hi>Goſpel, Grace</hi> and <hi>Righteouſneſs,</hi> his <hi>Joy,</hi> his <hi>Peace,</hi> his <hi>Strength,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>His <hi>mighty Arm Salvation</hi> brings, unto us now at length.</l>
               <l>With <hi>Wiſdom, Truth</hi> and <hi>Holineſs,</hi> which is to <hi>Sanctifie,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And <hi>cleanſe</hi> this little <hi>New-born Babe,</hi> which long in <hi>ſin</hi> did <hi>lye.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>This is the true <hi>Emanuel,</hi> that doth his People <hi>ſave,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>From all the <hi>ſins</hi> that they have done, that kept their <hi>Souls</hi> in <hi>Grav<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi>
               </l>
               <l>This is the <hi>Spirit</hi> that <hi>quickens</hi> us, this is the <hi>time</hi> of <hi>Love,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>When in our <hi>Blood</hi> we <hi>wallowing</hi> were, Oh then! <hi>What did <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </hi>
               </l>
               <l>Our <hi>Father</hi> could not, ſeeing he, by <hi>birth</hi> an <hi>Am'rite</hi> was.</l>
               <l>Nor <hi>Mother</hi> either, cauſe that ſhe came of the <hi>Hittits</hi>
               </l>
               <pb n="6" facs="tcp:62159:3"/>
               <l> Theſe fleſhly, earthly <hi>Canaanites,</hi> could not help in that day.</l>
               <l>Of the <hi>Souls</hi> great <hi>calamity,</hi> God <hi>only</hi> is its <hi>ſtay.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For Pitty, pitty no <hi>Eye</hi> had, on it, for to help when</l>
               <l>It was <hi>caſt out,</hi> and <hi>loath'd</hi> of all, <hi>Love</hi> to it God had then.</l>
               <l>He then did <hi>purge</hi> and <hi>purifie</hi> that <hi>Birth</hi> that is his own,</l>
               <l>The which is <hi>born</hi> of the <hi>Spirit,</hi> by a <hi>new Name</hi> is known.</l>
               <l>And <hi>He</hi> it is <hi>deliverance</hi> brings, from <hi>Satans Power</hi> and <hi>Might.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And hath tranſlated us into his <hi>Sons marvelous Light.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Whereby we <hi>wonder</hi> and <hi>admire,</hi> his <hi>Mercies</hi> manifold.</l>
               <l>And from his <hi>Truth</hi> cannot retire, his <hi>Truth</hi> doth make us bold,</l>
               <l>And valiant for it upon Earth, for which we <hi>All</hi> have loſt,</l>
               <l>For in our <hi>Building</hi> we ſate down, and did caſt up the <hi>Coſt.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And by the ſame our <hi>Souls</hi> have gain'd, let th'<hi>world</hi> go as it will,</l>
               <l>Let <hi>Life,</hi> or <hi>Death,</hi> or <hi>Sufferings</hi> come, ſo God <hi>be with us ſtill.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>This is the <hi>Teſt</hi> we have for God, in this we <hi>all agree,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>That of <hi>our ſelves</hi> no <hi>help</hi> we have; <hi>All</hi> is of <hi>Grace,</hi> and <hi>Free.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For <hi>Obligations</hi> we have none wherewith the Lord to <hi>tye.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But the <hi>Free Promiſes</hi> he makes, on them we do <hi>relye.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>So thoſe that true <hi>experience</hi> have, pray <hi>tell it</hi> to each other,</l>
               <l>What for their <hi>Souls</hi> the Lord hath done, be it <hi>Siſter</hi> or <hi>Brother.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>This is the <hi>Cauſe</hi> that we do <hi>Meet, together,</hi> it's Gods <hi>due,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>That we may <hi>ſerve</hi> and <hi>witneſs Him,</hi> by his <hi>Word,</hi> which is <hi>true.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For in the <hi>mouth</hi> of <hi>two</hi> or <hi>three,</hi> when they witneſs <hi>Allone,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Gods <hi>Word</hi> it is <hi>eſtabliſhed,</hi> and <hi>Truth</hi> prevails upon</l>
               <l>The <hi>Hearts</hi> and <hi>Souls</hi> of them that hear, both <hi>IN</hi> and <hi>O<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>T</hi> alſo,</l>
               <l>Whereby they the ſame <hi>Spirit know</hi> that is in many <hi>MO.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>This was the <hi>Order Paul</hi> did give the <hi>Co-rin-thi-ans</hi> to</l>
               <l>That to one place the Church ſhould come, and this alſo ſhould do.</l>
               <l>The <hi>Prophet</hi> or to <hi>Propheſie,</hi> to <hi>Judge</hi> the others were,</l>
               <l>By the <hi>ſame Spirit</hi> which they <hi>ſpoke,</hi> that to them <hi>Truths did clear.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And if amongſt them there did come, one that <hi>believed</hi> not,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Convicted</hi> then he is of all, and <hi>Judgement is his Lot.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And thus the <hi>ſecrets</hi> of his <hi>heart,</hi> all manifeſted be,</l>
               <l>So <hi>falling down upon his Face,</hi> then <hi>worſhip God</hi> will he;</l>
               <l>And of a truth report that God it is that <hi>lives in you.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>This way th'unlearned come to know the <hi>Way of God</hi> that's true.</l>
               <l>Here one by one may <hi>Propheſie,</hi> that all may hear and learn,</l>
               <l>And alſo may be <hi>comforted</hi> that to Gods Spirit <hi>turn.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>We <hi>Members</hi> of each others are, being <hi>Chriſts Body</hi> dear,</l>
               <l>Which <hi>he hath purchas'd with his Blood,</hi> and plac'd in us <hi>his Fear.</hi>
                  <pb facs="tcp:62159:4"/>
               </l>
               <pb n="7" facs="tcp:62159:4"/>
               <l> For we be they the which are built on the <hi>Foundation:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Of <hi>Prophets</hi> and <hi>Apoſtles</hi> to, <hi>Jeſus Chriſt's Corner-stone;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>In whom alſo the <hi>Building</hi> is <hi>fitly fram'd</hi> together:</l>
               <l>Grown unto an <hi>holy Temple,</hi> from which God will not ſever;</l>
               <l>For being <hi>Built</hi> together are, through the <hi>Almighty Spirit,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>An <hi>Habitation</hi> of God, the which he will <hi>Inherit.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And ſo the <hi>Head</hi> it cannot ſay to'th <hi>Foot, I need not thee;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Nor eke the <hi>Eye</hi> unto the <hi>Ear, O be thou gone from me:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For that the <hi>Body</hi> is but <hi>One,</hi> yet <hi>Members</hi> hath it <hi>Many;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Apeare there would <hi>Deformity,</hi> if lack there were of <hi>Any:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>This <hi>Body</hi> God hath temper'd ſo, the <hi>Members</hi> each with other</l>
               <l>That all ſhould have the ſelf ſame care, <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ncomly parts to cover;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Not to <hi>Rejoyce</hi> at <hi>Nakedneſs,</hi> as did that curſed <hi>Cham;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But as <hi>Japhet</hi> and bleſſed <hi>Shem,</hi> going backwards <hi>cover'd ſhame.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>So what is <hi>wanting</hi> in each one, a <hi>ſupply</hi> others have;</l>
               <l>To Miniſter unto each <hi>wants,</hi> by it their <hi>Soules</hi> to <hi>ſave.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And this all is by the ſame <hi>Spirit</hi> diverſities of <hi>Guifts,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>With different <hi>Miniſtrations,</hi> which <hi>Operate</hi> as thrifts;</l>
               <l>And yet it is but the <hi>ſame Lord,</hi> on whom we <hi>only call,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And the ſame God that <hi>Operates,</hi> and <hi>Worketh all in all.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>To own the <hi>Word</hi> of <hi>Wiſdom's</hi> given, the <hi>Word</hi> of <hi>Knowledg</hi> to,</l>
               <l>By the <hi>ſame Spirit</hi> another hath both <hi>Faith</hi> and <hi>Power</hi> to <hi>do;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And <hi>heal</hi> infirmities of <hi>Soules</hi> by working <hi>Miracl's</hi> many;</l>
               <l>And <hi>Propheſie</hi> and <hi>Deſcerning</hi> of <hi>Spirits</hi> where ther's <hi>any.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>All this the one and ſelf-ſame <hi>Spirit,</hi> which doth his <hi>members fill</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Dividing unto every man ſeverally as t'will.</l>
               <l>If this <hi>Church Figure</hi> be too bright for <hi>worldlings</hi> for to ſee,</l>
               <l>The uſe we make of our <hi>Meetings,</hi> in one <hi>Body</hi> to be,</l>
               <l>Take your own <hi>Body-figure-world</hi> the Countrys <hi>Members</hi> are,</l>
               <l>And each <hi>Comodity</hi> there <hi>grows,</hi> which are brought from on far;</l>
               <l>Theſe outward things the <hi>ſpirit</hi> are, of the world that's compleat,</l>
               <l>And every place where each doth go, are <hi>members</hi> of the great:</l>
               <l>And now God he hath plac't things ſo, in the whole ther's no want;</l>
               <l>Neither can any <hi>Country</hi> ſay, <hi>I've all, her's nothing ſcant.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And ſo each <hi>Country</hi> his <hi>Offring</hi> to each other ſends;</l>
               <l>Then theſe theſe <hi>gifts</hi> when they receive with others making mends,</l>
               <l>This order the worlds <hi>members</hi> have their wants for to ſupply;</l>
               <l>By ſending their <hi>abounding fruits</hi> for things they on rely;</l>
               <l>And where moſt <hi>trading</hi> there is uſ'd, Oh there they <hi>rich</hi> do grew,</l>
               <l>In gold, ſilver and pretious ſtones, this <hi>Babylon</hi> doth know.</l>
               <pb n="8" facs="tcp:62159:5"/>
               <l> By <hi>Schiſm, War,</hi> if Trading fail, Oh! then they do grow poor,</l>
               <l>By wanting of <hi>Commerce</hi> and <hi>Trade</hi> when they have ſpent thir ſtore:</l>
               <l>This being true why ſhall not we, as <hi>Members</hi> each of other,</l>
               <l>Bring forth our <hi>Offrings</hi> to the Lord, theſe may comfort another.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <head>Object.</head>
               <l>
                  <hi>Me thinks I hear ſome Critick ſay, O this is cunning made;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>For to compare Conventicles, to our great World and Trade:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>You count your ſelves ſo heavenly me thinks that you ſhould not,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>So paraphraſe on this fowl World leſt you receive a blot.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <head>Anſwer.</head>
               <l>My <hi>Anſwer</hi> is, 'tis for thy ſake thy hearing being but dull;</l>
               <l>That I ſpeak after the manner, of men, to thee in full.</l>
               <l>Moreover this Worlds Children are more wiſer much by far,</l>
               <l>In their own generation, then Lights own Children are.</l>
               <l>So to this generation, who mock, and ſcorn and fain,</l>
               <l>And for thy ſake I have digreſt, but now let me return,</l>
               <l>Unto Gods order in his Church, that all may hear and learn.</l>
               <l>This favour and incoragment it is held forth to all,</l>
               <l>That what of God revealed is to any, other ſhall</l>
               <l>Have liberty to ſpeak it forth, the Prophet which muſt hold,</l>
               <l>Their ſpirits being ſubject to the Prophet which is bold.</l>
               <l>So it the <hi>bruiſed reed</hi> breaks not, nor <hi>ſmoking flax</hi> doth quench,</l>
               <l>Till <hi>Judgment</hi> unto <hi>Victory</hi> comes, and <hi>Truth</hi> ſits on the <hi>Bench.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For that the knowledg of the Truth doth bring us all together;</l>
               <l>And from this Truth we cannot ſwerve, nor from each other ſever.</l>
               <l>For the profeſſion of our <hi>Faith</hi> together muſt hold faſt,</l>
               <l>For this our <hi>hope,</hi> our <hi>ſtay,</hi> our <hi>ſtrength,</hi> that muſt help us at laſt.</l>
               <l>For whether ſhall we go but there, where words of Life do ſpring,</l>
               <l>And from the roots doth hony drop, that makes poor <hi>Souls</hi> to ſing?</l>
               <l>Oh theſe Aſſemblies we may not at all, as ſome, forſake;</l>
               <l>Leaſt fiery indignation upon us God doth take.</l>
               <l>For that it is a wilful ſin, not to profeſs Gods Name;</l>
               <l>When before men we be brought forth, to ſuffer for the ſame.</l>
               <l>For where that two or three be come together in his Name,</l>
               <l>If the mid'ſt of them he will be, who can keep from the ſame?</l>
               <l>For that in him the <hi>Treaſures</hi> be, of <hi>Wiſdome Knowledg</hi> to;</l>
               <l>Which he gives to his Children dear whoſe hearts to him are true.</l>
               <l>In him's the <hi>Oracle</hi> of God, who doth his People teach,</l>
               <l>In their hearts how to worſhip him, ſo they it forth do preach.</l>
               <pb n="9" facs="tcp:62159:5"/>
               <l> And not <hi>Meeting</hi> it was the cauſe of <hi>Hearing</hi> ſome were dull,</l>
               <l>Which made things hard for to be <hi>ſaid</hi> or <hi>uttered</hi> to the full.</l>
               <l>For there were ſome that for their time, ought <hi>Teachers</hi> for to be;</l>
               <l>And yet have need one <hi>teach</hi> again firſt <hi>Principles</hi> to ſee;</l>
               <l>And were become ſuch as had need of <hi>Milk</hi> and not ſtrong <hi>Meat;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For every one that uſeth <hi>Milk</hi> unskilful is to <hi>Eat.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Or feed upon the <hi>Righteous Word,</hi> for that a <hi>Babe</hi> is he;</l>
               <l>To him ſtrong <hi>Meat</hi> doth not belong, with him t'will not agree.</l>
               <l>But thoſe that are of riper age, to them it doth belong;</l>
               <l>E'en thoſe that by reaſon of uſe, have their ſences made ſtrong;</l>
               <l>Being exerciſed do deſerne between both <hi>good and evil</hi>
               </l>
               <l>So in Gods Truth we are kept from, the <hi>lying, murdering Devil.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Job</hi> that was <hi>juſt</hi> and <hi>perfect</hi> both, ſuch <hi>Meetings</hi> did come to,</l>
               <l>With other of the <hi>ſons of God,</hi> as <hi>Gods ſons</hi> now do do;</l>
               <l>And though <hi>Sathan</hi> did alſo come, 'twas for <hi>advantage</hi> ſake,</l>
               <l>To be <hi>Informer,</hi> and <hi>accuſe,</hi> that he their <hi>goods</hi> might take,</l>
               <l>And though that he Commiſſion got to take all in his power,</l>
               <l>By <hi>Sabins</hi> and <hi>Caldeans</hi> to, as he doth at this hour,</l>
               <l>Perſwading God <hi>they him would Curſe,</hi> if he'll but let him tuch</l>
               <l>Their <hi>goods,</hi> or <hi>ought elſe</hi> that they have, no <hi>Meetings</hi> would be ſuch.</l>
               <l>And yet again there was a day when the <hi>Sons of God Came</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>For to preſent themſelves before the Lord,</hi> they are the ſame,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Who</hi> ſtill hold faſt <hi>Integrity,</hi> although that he doth move</l>
               <l>'Gainſt him, and us, both to deſtroy yet we'll not Curſe our <hi>Love.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Yea <hi>Skin</hi> for <hi>Skin,</hi> and all we have, yea <hi>Bone</hi> and <hi>Fleſh alſo</hi>
               </l>
               <l>We hope we ſhall to him give up, rather then <hi>Curſe</hi> him mo.</l>
               <l>For how can we commit this ſin, not to <hi>walk</hi> in <hi>Gods way,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>When we ſuch large experience have of him our <hi>ſtrength</hi> and <hi>ſtay</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But I ſhall rather here break forth, it being now the <hi>Spring,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>By <hi>Chirping</hi> praiſe our <hi>Gad</hi> of <hi>Love,</hi> Who can but to him <hi>ſing</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And in my <hi>ſong</hi> I ſhall you ſhew, What theſe our <hi>Meetings</hi> be,</l>
               <l>I <hi>figured</hi> have in many things, yet all in <hi>Truth</hi> agree.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>We are the <hi>Tabernacle</hi> of the <hi>Con-gre-ga-ti-on,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>The which the Lord in Earth reſerves to call his <hi>Name</hi> upon;</l>
               <l>In us the <hi>Ark</hi> and <hi>Covenant</hi> is and <hi>Mercy-ſeat</hi> we ſee,</l>
               <l>With <hi>Pot</hi> of <hi>Heavenly Manna</hi> to, to us the <hi>Cher'bims</hi> flee;</l>
               <l>With us alſo there is the <hi>Rod,</hi> that <hi>buddeth</hi> and is <hi>green,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Of the <hi>High Prieſt</hi> from <hi>Judah</hi> came, as plainly may be ſeen:</l>
               <l>Here is the <hi>Golden Cenſer</hi> to, in which is <hi>heavenly fire,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And here's the <hi>Table</hi> of <hi>Shew-bread,</hi> What can you more deſire</l>
               <pb n="10" facs="tcp:62159:6"/>
               <l> And here's the <hi>Cap of Bleſſing</hi> to, in our <hi>Communion,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>This <hi>Blood</hi> our <hi>Souls</hi> muſt alſo <hi>purge,</hi> for <hi>other help</hi> we've none.</l>
               <l>And if that you <hi>Baptiz'd</hi> would be, oh here are <hi>Baptim's</hi> many,</l>
               <l>Here's <hi>Water, Fire, Suffrings, Death;</hi> here you cant miſs of any.</l>
               <l>With us there is the <hi>Laver</hi> of <hi>Re-ge-ne-ra-ti-on.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For <hi>Juda</hi> and <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi> it <hi>cleanſeth Mount Sion.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And <hi>Fire-Baptiſm</hi>'s alſo here, the <hi>Holy Ghost, Gods Word,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>A <hi>Suffering-Baptiſm</hi> doth appear, proceeding from the <hi>Sword.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>A more <hi>ſecret Baptiſm</hi> there is, cannot be ſpoke with <hi>breath,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And this is that <hi>Baptiſm</hi> of Chriſt, <hi>Baptiz'd</hi> into his <hi>Death.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>This is no <hi>Outward viſible Sign,</hi> not <hi>ſignified</hi> ſo,</l>
               <l>But <hi>ſeparates</hi> man from his <hi>Lusts</hi> that always ſtood his <hi>foe.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Thus in his <hi>fleſh Chriſt he took up,</hi> the <hi>Comforts</hi> of <hi>Mans Life,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And laid them down at <hi>Gods own Will,</hi> to <hi>reconcile</hi> the <hi>Strife;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For <hi>God</hi> it was <hi>that was in Chriſt, the World to reconcile,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Now in his ſtead <hi>Embaſſadors,</hi> hath ſent to us the <hi>vile:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Though 'twas not <hi>him</hi> did the <hi>Offence,</hi> but was the <hi>Offended,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Yet his <hi>Embaſſadors pray us</hi> to be <hi>re-con-ci-led.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Here's <hi>Grace</hi> indeed! not only <hi>free,</hi> but doth a <hi>begging come,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And <hi>Meſſengers</hi> t'intreat the <hi>World</hi> to <hi>accept</hi> this <hi>Ranſome.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>The which none could lay down for it, but <hi>He</hi> of's <hi>own accord</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Did <hi>purchas't</hi> with his <hi>precious Blood,</hi> and ſo of <hi>right</hi> is <hi>Lord.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Yet doth not uſe <hi>Commanding Power,</hi> but <hi>Love</hi> is his own way;</l>
               <l>And thoſe that will not <hi>this</hi> ſhall <hi>Rule,</hi> as <hi>Enemies</hi> he will <hi>ſlay.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But this <hi>laſt Baptiſme</hi> doth ſet the <hi>True Baptiſmes</hi> on</l>
               <l>The <hi>anſwer of a good Conſcience,</hi> by Chriſts <hi>Reſurrection.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For as <hi>Chriſts fleſh</hi> it <hi>ſuffered,</hi> the <hi>ſame mind</hi> we muſt have,</l>
               <l>No longer in our <hi>ſins</hi> to <hi>live,</hi> which to our <hi>Soul's</hi> a <hi>Grave,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But now the <hi>Goſpel</hi> it is <hi>preacht,</hi> the <hi>dead ſleeper's awake,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Yea he is come to <hi>Judgement</hi> to, God <hi>Life</hi> to him doth make.</l>
               <l>For that he would no longer have our <hi>Souls</hi> in <hi>Priſon lye,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But by his <hi>quickning Spirit</hi> preach, and <hi>free-ed</hi> us thereby,</l>
               <l>Who ſometime <hi>diſobedient</hi> were, yet God did ſuffer <hi>long,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Waiting as in the dayes of <hi>Noa</hi> (who griev'd his <hi>Spirit</hi> ſtrong.)</l>
               <l>And now unto the <hi>Will</hi> of <hi>God</hi> he doth <hi>ſubjection</hi> give,</l>
               <l>No more unto the <hi>Gentiles Will</hi> reſolveth he to live.</l>
               <l>This is that <hi>Tabernacle</hi> which, <hi>down nere ſhall any take,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Nor <hi>Cord</hi> thereof ſhall <hi>broken</hi> be, <hi>removd</hi> ſhall be no <hi>Stake.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For here the <hi>Glorious Lord</hi> will be, <hi>Rivers</hi> and <hi>Streams</hi> whereon,</l>
               <l>No <hi>Gally</hi> nor no <hi>gallant Ship</hi> at all ſhall paſs upon</l>
               <pb n="11" facs="tcp:62159:6"/>
               <l> For that mens <hi>Tacklings</hi> looſed are, their ſtrength at <hi>Ours</hi> doth fall,</l>
               <l>They cannot well ſtrengthen their <hi>Maſt,</hi> or ſpread abroad their <hi>Sail,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For tis the <hi>Lord</hi> that is our <hi>King,</hi> and our <hi>Lawgiver</hi> to,</l>
               <l>How can we then lack any thing for ought he bids us do.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Oh this alſo is <hi>Wiſdoms Gate,</hi> Why he you then ſo <hi>mad?</hi>
               </l>
               <l>If ever that your <hi>Souls</hi> be <hi>ſav'd,</hi> to's <hi>Church God muſt you add.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Wiſdom cryed</hi> hath <hi>without,</hi> and <hi>uttered voice in ſtreet,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Yea in the Market place ſhe calls,</hi> where <hi>Phariſees</hi> do <hi>greet;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>In the <hi>chief Places</hi> of <hi>Concorſe,</hi> the <hi>opening of the Gate,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Yea in their <hi>great Aſſemblies</hi> to, where <hi>multitudes</hi> were ſate;</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>How long, ye ſimple ones will ye, love your ſimplicity?</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Turn ye</hi> unto this <hi>Church</hi> that ye may <hi>eat</hi> and <hi>live</hi> thereby.</l>
               <l>And <hi>Scorners, Why do ye delight in this your ſcorning Trade,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>You being <hi>Fools, Knowledge</hi> do <hi>hate,</hi> tis <hi>ſin</hi> thus hath you <hi>made.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>At <hi>Gods reproof</hi> if now you'l <hi>turn,</hi> he'll <hi>pour</hi> on you his <hi>Spirit,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>His <hi>words</hi> unto you he'll <hi>make known,</hi> that you may <hi>Life inherit.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But this much know, if you <hi>refuſe,</hi> and do not him <hi>regard,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But do his <hi>Councel ſet at nought,</hi> with this he'll you reward;</l>
               <l>For <hi>mocking</hi> he will <hi>mock again</hi> at your <hi>Calamity,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And <hi>laugh</hi> when as your <hi>fear doth come,</hi> it's <hi>deſolation</hi> nigh,</l>
               <l>Then you may <hi>call,</hi> but <hi>God</hi> will now to <hi>anſwer give</hi> at all,</l>
               <l>Becauſe you did not <hi>anſwer</hi> him, when he to you did <hi>call.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For you none of his <hi>Counſel</hi> would, <hi>Reproof's</hi> you did deſpite,</l>
               <l>And would not chooſe the <hi>Fear</hi> of <hi>God,</hi> but hated <hi>Knowledge wiſe;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Therefore the <hi>fruit</hi> of <hi>your own way</hi> is <hi>meat</hi> for you to <hi>eat,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Your <hi>own devices</hi> you ſhall fill, who ſhut out <hi>Wiſdom great.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>In <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>s</hi> the <hi>Time</hi> is <hi>come to paſs,</hi> laſt dayes <hi>pro-phe-ſi-ed,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>That the Mountain of the Lords Houſe ſhould be eſtabliſhed;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And on the <hi>Top</hi> exalted is, above all <hi>barren Hills,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And many <hi>People</hi> to us <hi>flow,</hi> thus <hi>God</hi> his <hi>Houſe</hi> now <hi>fills,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And we his <hi>People</hi> bid you <hi>come,</hi> to this the <hi>Lords Mountain.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>It is the <hi>Houſe</hi> of <hi>Jacobs God,</hi> tis he o're it doth <hi>Raign.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Here he doth <hi>teach</hi> us his <hi>own Way,</hi> the <hi>Pathes</hi> that we ſhould <hi>walk,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>From out of <hi>Sion</hi> flowes that <hi>Law</hi> whereof we <hi>joy</hi> to <hi>talk,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>This is the <hi>Word</hi> which <hi>God</hi> the <hi>Lord</hi> ſends from <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>That doth among the <hi>Nations Judge, rebuking</hi> much of them.</l>
               <l>So that they have their <hi>Swords</hi> now <hi>beat</hi> into <hi>Plow, ſhares</hi> we ſee.</l>
               <l>And their <hi>Spears</hi> into <hi>Pruning-Hooks,</hi> this <hi>LOVE</hi> makes <hi>all agree.</hi>
               </l>
               <pb n="12" facs="tcp:62159:7"/>
               <l> So <hi>Nation</hi> doth not lift up <hi>Sword,</hi> for <hi>Eſau</hi> doth embrace</l>
               <l>His Brother <hi>Jacob</hi> in his <hi>Armes,</hi> this makes War ceaſe. 'Tis Grace,</l>
               <l>So we with <hi>Iſay</hi> bid you come, to this houſe with accord,</l>
               <l>Deſiring you to walk with us, in the <hi>Light</hi> of the <hi>Lord.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>We are the <hi>City</hi> on a <hi>Hill,</hi> there ſet that all may ſee,</l>
               <l>Therefore alwayes in <hi>Cottages,</hi> ſtill this we cannot be;</l>
               <l>For that we are not to be hid, but ſet there to be ſhown,</l>
               <l>And <hi>that</hi> through the <hi>Power</hi> of <hi>God</hi> to others ſhould be known:</l>
               <l>Which is the <hi>Light,</hi> the <hi>Chriſt</hi> in us, the <hi>Hope of Glory to;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And doth caſt out the <hi>Reprobate,</hi> this work he is to do,</l>
               <l>The <hi>Blind</hi> make ſee, and <hi>Deaf</hi> to hear, tho <hi>Mountebancks</hi> do rage,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Leapers</hi> are cleans'd, &amp; <hi>Dumb</hi> do ſpeak, <hi>this</hi> throws them <hi>off the ſtage</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And this alſo is freely to, we witneſs it truly,</l>
               <l>And if that we ſhould hold our peace <hi>ſtones</hi> would againſt us cry.</l>
               <l>For what are we more then wrought <hi>ſtone,</hi> 'tis God that doth us raiſe</l>
               <l>To he the ſeed of <hi>Abraham,</hi> for to ſhew forth his Praiſe:</l>
               <l>Tho in the <hi>Wilderneſs</hi> we're ſquard, and now appear but looſe,</l>
               <l>Yet being brought together all, we do make God a Houſe;</l>
               <l>Whereby the <hi>Workemans Worke</hi> is ſeen for that he hath them <hi>tryed,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And made them like the <hi>Corner-ſtone,</hi> to anſwer every ſide;</l>
               <l>Yea <hi>Judgement</hi> to the <hi>Plumet</hi> hangs, and <hi>Righteouſneſs</hi> to'th <hi>Line,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For to make all <hi>upright</hi> and <hi>true,</hi> according to his <hi>mine.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Theſe <hi>living ſtones</hi> together ſet, may plainly ſee each other</l>
               <l>The <hi>Mighty workmanſhip of God,</hi> in <hi>Siſter</hi> and in <hi>Brother,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Yea tis the <hi>Standard</hi> of the <hi>Lord,</hi> the <hi>Enſigne</hi> he hath ſer,</l>
               <l>For all <hi>Nations</hi> to <hi>flock</hi> unto, tho <hi>Small things day</hi> is yet.</l>
               <l>And though that we be <hi>Quakers</hi> call'd, by moſt people in <hi>ſcorn,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Yet we the <hi>true Aſſembly</hi> be, and <hi>Church of the Firſt-born.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For in our <hi>heart</hi> God he doth <hi>dwell,</hi> whoſe <hi>Spirit is a Sword,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Which was the cauſe that we were made to <hi>tremble at his Word.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And when the Lord with <hi>Odours</hi> ſweet doth this his own <hi>Houſe fill,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Oh then all others that <hi>paſs by,</hi> its <hi>ſweetneſs</hi> favour will.</l>
               <l>And if that any <hi>Lydia</hi> come, that is to God ſo dear,</l>
               <l>Whoſe <hi>heart</hi> the Lord hath <hi>o-pen-ed,</hi> ſhe'll <hi>feed</hi> upon our <hi>chear.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For in theſe <hi>publick Mountains God</hi> to all will make his <hi>Feaſt,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And <hi>Meſſengers</hi> to'th <hi>high way ſend,</hi> for to <hi>invite his Gueſts.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Theſe are the <hi>Feaſts</hi> of <hi>Charity,</hi> made by the <hi>God</hi> of <hi>Love,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>On <hi>Heavenly Manna</hi> here we <hi>feed,</hi> which comes from <hi>God above.</hi>
               </l>
               <pb n="13" facs="tcp:62159:7"/>
               <l> We being many are one <hi>Bread,</hi> of which we <hi>partake all,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And when we'r <hi>hungry</hi> doth us <hi>feed,</hi> both now, and ever ſhall.</l>
               <l>This alſo is Gods <hi>Candleſtick,</hi> in which his <hi>Candle</hi>'s ſet,</l>
               <l>And <hi>lighteth</hi> thoſe be in the <hi>Houſe,</hi> and is for others yet.</l>
               <l>The <hi>Woman</hi> having loſt her piece of <hi>ſilver,</hi> ſought with <hi>pain,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And when that ſhe had found it out, t'her <hi>Neighbours</hi> cryes amain;</l>
               <l>Contented not within her ſelf theſe favours up to frowl,</l>
               <l>But ſhe muſt tell to others to, what is <hi>done for her Soul.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>This was the <hi>Sheep</hi> that went <hi>aſtray</hi> into the <hi>Wilderneſs,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But the good <hi>Shepherd</hi> he is come, and brought it to the <hi>reſt.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Oh therefore <hi>Neighbours, neighbours</hi> come, let us <hi>rejoyce</hi> together,</l>
               <l>And <hi>praiſes</hi> in his <hi>Houſe</hi> let's ſing, for <hi>ever,</hi> and for <hi>ever.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>This is the <hi>HIVE</hi> alſo to which the <hi>BEES</hi> do <hi>honey</hi> bring,</l>
               <l>Which they do gather from God's <hi>Flowers;</hi> there they <hi>together ſing,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Which is to him a ſavory thing, and pleaſant to his <hi>Heart,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Becauſe 'tis what comes from <hi>himſelf,</hi> in us he doth it <hi>dart:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>This is the <hi>Sacrifice</hi> of god, which in them doth <hi>ariſe.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Being from <hi>broken contrite hearts, God will it not deſpiſe.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Hither the <hi>Virgins Wiſe</hi> alſo, are altogether <hi>come,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Each having <hi>Oyl</hi> in his <hi>Veſſel,</hi> tho in their <hi>Lamps burns ſome.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Theſe <hi>Lamps</hi> being altogether <hi>trim'd,</hi> they do make a great <hi>Light,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Which is the <hi>brightneſs</hi> of Gods <hi>Love,</hi> held forth to <hi>Peoples ſight,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>To this <hi>bright riſing</hi> all muſt come, which is as <hi>Heavens Gate,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And with <hi>Oyl</hi> in their <hi>Veſſels wait,</hi> leſt they do <hi>come too late.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>This is the place that is <hi>dreadful,</hi> in which <hi>Gods preſence is,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Were <hi>two</hi> or <hi>three together be,</hi> to <hi>praiſe</hi> the <hi>Name</hi> that's <hi>his.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>This needs muſt be the <hi>Houſe of God,</hi> where <hi>Angels</hi> do <hi>deſcend,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And thoſe that <hi>meet</hi> in <hi>Gods pure fear,</hi> he doubtleſs will <hi>defend.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>This is not any <hi>New thing</hi> now, as if't had <hi>never been,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But this hath been in in <hi>Ages</hi> paſt, as plainly hath been ſeen.</l>
               <l>This is the Houſe that <hi>David</hi> lov'd, even the <hi>dwelling place,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Wherein Gods <hi>honour</hi> ſtill remains, in hearts full fraught with <hi>Grace,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And <hi>David</hi> bud all here to come, and that with <hi>one accord.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Who God did <hi>fear,</hi> to them <hi>he'll tell, the goodneſs of the Lord.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>What for his Soul the Lord had done,</hi> which he for him did <hi>ſave,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Which was the <hi>Branch</hi> of <hi>Jeſſe Stem,</hi> and rais'd him from the <hi>Grave,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Becauſe he would not ſuffer him, being his <hi>holy One,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>That ought to him belonging ſhould, ere <hi>ſee corruption.</hi>
               </l>
               <pb n="14" facs="tcp:62159:8"/>
               <l> Therefore for this doth <hi>Davids Preach,</hi> and to the <hi>living tell,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>In the great <hi>Congregation</hi> of <hi>Saints</hi> that do <hi>excel,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>In whom was only his <hi>delight,</hi> which <hi>faithful</hi> were and <hi>true</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And that in <hi>Virtue</hi> did <hi>excel,</hi> whoſe <hi>hearts</hi> God had made <hi>New.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Theſe are the <hi>Living Waters</hi> which, are both the <hi>laſt</hi> and <hi>firſt,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Therefore muſt all that ſeek for <hi>Life</hi> come <hi>here</hi> to <hi>quench</hi> their <hi>thirſt.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Without <hi>money,</hi> and without <hi>price, Come ye,</hi> do <hi>buy,</hi> and <hi>eat,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Both <hi>Wine</hi> and <hi>Milk,</hi> Why do you <hi>ſpend money</hi> for that's <hi>no meat?</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And your <hi>Labour</hi> alſo for that which doth not <hi>ſatisfie,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For it is not the <hi>Bread of Life;</hi> therefore you <hi>eat</hi> and <hi>dye.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But hark with <hi>diligence</hi> to <hi>God, oat ye</hi> that <hi>which is good,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And let your <hi>Soul delight</hi> it <hi>ſelf</hi> in <hi>fatneſs,</hi> its own <hi>food.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Incline</hi> your <hi>ear,</hi> yea come and <hi>hear,</hi> and then your <hi>Souls</hi> ſhall <hi>live.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>The <hi>Covenant ſure</hi> of <hi>Mercy pure,</hi> of <hi>David</hi> he will <hi>give.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Our <hi>Meetings</hi> they do <hi>witneſs Him,</hi> that muſt the <hi>People lead,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And he is our <hi>Commander</hi> to, our <hi>Peace, Light, Life</hi> and <hi>Bread.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Thus being <hi>met</hi> in <hi>Gods pure fear,</hi> we then the <hi>Cyſterns</hi> are</l>
               <l>Which he of <hi>living water clear,</hi> doth ſend to us from <hi>far.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And therefore from this <hi>evil</hi> to, when that it doth appear,</l>
               <l>All <hi>People</hi> we adviſe to <hi>come, from Cyſterns</hi> are not <hi>clear:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For theſe be ſuch, <hi>Men to themſelves,</hi> who have forſook the Lord,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Hewed,</hi> the which no <hi>Water</hi> will, of <hi>Life</hi> to them afford.</l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Theſe <hi>Meetings</hi> alſo <hi>Malachy</hi> did ſpeak of in his time,</l>
               <l>Wherein <hi>they that did fear the Lord,</hi> and were <hi>all of one mine</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>
                     <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nto each other oft did ſpeak,</hi> to which <hi>the the Lord gave ear,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And then a <hi>Book of remembrance, he wrote,</hi> as doth appear;</l>
               <l>For that they are and ſhall be his, for ever he'll them <hi>ſpare,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>As <hi>Man</hi> doth <hi>ſpare</hi> his <hi>ſerving Son,</hi> for they are <hi>Jewels rare.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>Theſe <hi>Meetings</hi> then were alſo kept in ſuch an <hi>evil time</hi>
               </l>
               <l>When none but th' <hi>wicked were ſet up,</hi> for <hi>goodneſs was a crime:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>The <hi>Proud</hi> were then <hi>the Happy oalld, wicked workers ſet up,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Yet then <hi>Gods People</hi> they did <hi>Meet,</hi> tho <hi>Sufferings were their Cup.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <l>
                  <hi>Betheſdas Pool</hi> a figure was, of this our <hi>Meeting Place,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Whereas both <hi>Lame</hi> and <hi>Blind</hi> muſt <hi>wait,</hi> for Gods <hi>deſcending Grace</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And in much <hi>patience</hi> wait his <hi>Will,</hi> till that the <hi>Angel move,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And the <hi>Waters</hi> with <hi>virtue fill,</hi> to <hi>heal,</hi> this is Gods <hi>Love.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And therefore be not <hi>too haſty,</hi> but wait upon <hi>Gods leaſure,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For all <hi>Infirmities</hi> he <hi>heals,</hi> and therein <hi>taketh pleaſure.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <lg>
               <pb n="15" facs="tcp:62159:8"/>
               <l>
                  <hi>Samarias</hi> Mountain tis likewiſe, wherein is <hi>Jacobs Well;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Which ſprings forth to <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 word">
                     <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                  </gap> 
                  <hi>Life,</hi> of <hi>this</hi> many can tell.</l>
               <l>Here is the true <hi>Ho-ly Water,</hi> of <hi>Life,</hi> both <hi>pure</hi> and <hi>clear,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>This is not that the <hi>Pope</hi> doth make, wherewith he men doth <hi>jear;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But this is that that God doth <hi>give,</hi> whereof when men do <hi>drink,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Out of their Belly <hi>Rivers flow,</hi> much more than they can think.</l>
               <l>Here when Gods <hi>People</hi> they do <hi>Meet,</hi> whoſe <hi>zeal</hi> is as a <hi>flame,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Which maketh oft their <hi>hearts to burn,</hi> wh<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                     <desc>•…</desc>
                  </gap> declares <hi>his Fame.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Of which the <hi>Scripture</hi> it is <hi>full,</hi> yet is a <hi>Book that's ſeald,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Which neither <hi>learnt</hi> nor <hi>unlearned,</hi> to any hath <hi>reveald.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For the <hi>Veil</hi> being or'e their heart, when <hi>Moſes</hi> he is <hi>read,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>How then can they know <hi>Chriſts own day</hi> though it be <hi>propheſi'd?</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Though <hi>precept</hi> upon <hi>precept</hi> be, yet they are nere the near,</l>
               <l>And <hi>Line</hi> upon <hi>line,</hi> they <hi>ſee not,</hi> being without <hi>Gods Fear.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Of this <hi>Iſaiah</hi> did complain and grievd for in his time,</l>
               <l>This was the cauſe of <hi>Ignorance,</hi> and <hi>darkneſs</hi> of the <hi>mine,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>A <hi>ſinful Nation</hi> he them call'd, a <hi>ſeed of evil-doers,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Who had the <hi>Lord forſaken,</hi> and in <hi>corrupt wayes</hi> were <hi>goers;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>So <hi>laden</hi> with <hi>iniquity,</hi> thoſe things they did not <hi>know,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Which <hi>daily</hi> unto them was <hi>read,</hi> their <hi>Veil</hi> did <hi>blind</hi> them ſo.</l>
               <l>For <hi>Rulers</hi> they of <hi>Sodom</hi> were, which is the <hi>Earthly Power,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Inhabitants</hi> of <hi>Gomorrah,</hi> which cloggs them every hour.</l>
               <l>So all theſe wicked worldly things that are ſet in the heart,</l>
               <l>Muſt all with Gods <hi>pure fire</hi> be <hi>burnt,</hi> though man do feel the <hi>ſmart;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Yea be moved out of its place, by Gods <hi>Almighty Power,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For this ſame <hi>power</hi> of God alone, will all of it <hi>devour.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And this <hi>Word-fire,</hi> the virtue hath, not only for to <hi>burn,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But give <hi>Light, Life,</hi> yea <hi>Heat</hi> and <hi>Power,</hi> to them that of it <hi>learn,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And therefore tho <hi>dark, cold</hi> and <hi>dead,</hi> without <hi>power</hi> or <hi>ſtrength,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Yet come to this <hi>Light, Living-Word,</hi> 'twill <hi>raiſe</hi> you all at length.</l>
               <l>We therefore in our <hi>Meetings</hi> have known this <hi>Refiners fire,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Which is to <hi>take off all the droſs;</hi> from it do not retire.</l>
               <l>For as in outward <hi>fire</hi> we ſee, when <hi>coals abroad be ſpread,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>The <hi>Light,</hi> the <hi>Life,</hi> and <hi>Heat</hi> goes out, and all comes to be <hi>dead;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But when again <hi>together brought,</hi> and <hi>kindled freſh anew,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Oh then each <hi>coal rejoyceth much,</hi> when <hi>fire</hi> is put thereto.</l>
               <l>Which is the <hi>end</hi> for which they are <hi>created</hi> of the Lord,</l>
               <l>That <hi>Light, Life, Heat</hi> and <hi>Comfort</hi> to, each other may afford.</l>
               <l>And if our <hi>Candles,</hi> being <hi>Light,</hi> we can by no means <hi>hide,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But muſt come to our <hi>Candlestick,</hi> what ever doth betide;</l>
               <pb n="16" facs="tcp:62159:9"/>
               <l> Becauſe that we know it is <hi>night,</hi> in which many do <hi>grope,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Therefore we do bring forth our <hi>Light,</hi> to give to them ſome <hi>hope:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Which is the <hi>Goſpel-power</hi> of God, that <hi>Satan</hi> can't <hi>abide,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But ſeeks our <hi>Candle</hi> to <hi>put out,</hi> that he <hi>Gods power</hi> may <hi>hide.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For he the <hi>Prince</hi> of <hi>darkneſs is,</hi> and would have all be ſo,</l>
               <l>And if't be asked, <hi>Where Light may ſhine?</hi> He preſent cryes, <hi>No, no.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Then ſeen his <hi>wicked works</hi> would be, that to them are the <hi>Gate,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Of their <hi>Deſtruction,</hi> therefore he, of all things it doth <hi>hate.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>When firſt in <hi>fleſh</hi> Chriſt did appear, though in a <hi>Child young born,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>He <hi>muſters</hi> then up all his <hi>power,</hi> for to deſtroy the <hi>Form;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And led them then to <hi>Bethlehem,</hi> with this his <hi>falſe intent,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>By which <hi>dark Power</hi> he did <hi>devour</hi> many poor <hi>Innocent.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Herod</hi> he then troubled full ſore, with all <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Perſwading him the <hi>Child was born</hi> ſhould <hi>Rule</hi> both <hi>him</hi> and <hi>them,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But this was then another thing, than <hi>Worldly Rule</hi> to have,</l>
               <l>For if that he would be a <hi>King,</hi> the People he muſt <hi>ſave.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But his <hi>Kingdom</hi> it is not <hi>here,</hi> nor do his <hi>Servants fight,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But in mens <hi>hearts</hi> it doth <hi>appear,</hi> and <hi>guides</hi> them to the <hi>Right:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>From whence all <hi>wrath, ſtrife</hi> and <hi>envy,</hi> are ſhut out, with all <hi>Wars,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And all in <hi>Peace</hi> and <hi>Love</hi> do <hi>Live</hi> without <hi>hatred</hi> or <hi>Jars.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>So that the ground and cauſe of <hi>Fear,</hi> we may from men remove,</l>
               <l>No other <hi>Principle</hi> we have, but unto all men <hi>Love.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And therefore are our <hi>Meetings now,</hi> not kept in any <hi>ſpight,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Of <hi>King,</hi> or <hi>Law,</hi> or <hi>Parliament,</hi> but purely in <hi>Gods ſight.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For ſhall not <hi>Sions Daughter ſhine,</hi> now that her <hi>Light</hi> is come,</l>
               <l>Or can her <hi>Glory</hi> once be <hi>hid,</hi> that's <hi>radiant</hi> as the <hi>Sun?</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For that ſhe hath her <hi>Pride</hi> caſt off, in this the Lords own <hi>Day,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>(Her <hi>haughty Looks,</hi> and <hi>ſtretch'd out Neck,</hi> with <hi>wanton Eyes</hi> do <hi>ſtay;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Her <hi>walking, mincing, twinkling Feet,</hi> her <hi>Bravery</hi> full ſoon,</l>
               <l>Her <hi>Chains,</hi> her <hi>Braſlets,</hi> and <hi>Mufflers, Round tyers</hi> like the <hi>Moon;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Her <hi>Bonnets</hi> and <hi>Leg-ornaments,</hi> her <hi>Head-band</hi> and <hi>Ear-rings,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>
                  <hi>Changable Suits</hi> of <hi>Apparel,</hi> her <hi>Wimples, Criſping-pins:</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Alſo her <hi>Glaſſes, Hoods</hi> and <hi>Veils,</hi> theſe Burthens God endures,</l>
               <l>And all her <hi>Heavenly outward ſhews,</hi> which ſeen pleaſant <hi>Pictures.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Theſe her own <hi>righteous filthy Raggs,</hi> her <hi>Covering</hi> and <hi>Garment,</hi>)</l>
               <l>And th' <hi>Meek,</hi> and <hi>quiet Spirit</hi> hath, took for her <hi>Ornament.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>Though Captive ſhe was to thoſe things, ſhe hath <hi>ſhook off the duſt,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>And put on beautiful Garments, the which ſhe wore at firſt.</l>
               <l>This is the <hi>Bride</hi> that bids you <hi>Come,</hi> the <hi>Spirit</hi> ſaith the ſame,</l>
               <l>And whoſoever <hi>thirſts,</hi> and <hi>will,</hi> may <hi>come</hi> unto this <hi>Name.</hi>
               </l>
               <pb n="17" facs="tcp:62159:9"/>
               <l> The which we are <hi>gathered unto</hi> in all the <hi>Peoples</hi> ſight,</l>
               <l>Being Chriſts <hi>Bride</hi> and <hi>Body</hi> too, and for the <hi>World</hi> a <hi>Light.</hi>]</l>
               <l>So under <hi>Bed</hi> nor <hi>Buſhel</hi> nere muſt we at all be <hi>hid,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But on the <hi>Table</hi> muſt be ſet, a <hi>Light</hi> for the <hi>Blinded.</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For this <hi>worlds god</hi> mens minds doth <hi>blind,</hi> with <hi>riches, cares</hi> &amp; <hi>fears,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>He would not have this <hi>Goſpel ſhine,</hi> that theſe <hi>foggs</hi> all would <hi>clear;</hi>
               </l>
               <l>But would have all in <hi>darkneſs</hi> dwell, this is his <hi>Ellement,</hi>
               </l>
               <l>For with this <hi>Light</hi> he <hi>angry</hi> is, and with us <hi>diſcontent.</hi>
               </l>
            </lg>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>Something about SPEAKING, Who is to Speak, or What to be ſpoken?</head>
               <lg>
                  <head>Object.</head>
                  <l>BUT ſome may ſay, <hi>You many times ſit ſilent we do ſee,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And there is no ſpeaking at all, with us this don't agree.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Anſw.</head>
                  <l>My <hi>Anſwer</hi> is, If any have <hi>Gods Oracle</hi> we'll hear,</l>
                  <l>For that is it <hi>expells</hi> all <hi>Miſts,</hi> and makes the <hi>Air clear.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For this doth firſt the <hi>Veſſel cleanſe</hi> from whence it doth proceed,</l>
                  <l>That firſt <hi>believes,</hi> and therefore <hi>ſpeaks,</hi> to this we're all <hi>agreed.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Faiths work</hi> is firſt to <hi>cleanſe</hi> the <hi>heart</hi> from all <hi>hypocriſies,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Than may it help for to <hi>pluck out, Motes</hi> from their <hi>Brothers eyes;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For how the <hi>unconverted</hi> ſhall at all <hi>ſtrengthen</hi> his <hi>Brother,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For then they do <hi>condemn themſelves,</hi> by <hi>teaching</hi> of another,</l>
                  <l>How ſhall the <hi>Thief</hi> at all <hi>exhort</hi> another not to <hi>ſteal,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or the <hi>diſeas'd Phyſician</hi> tell others he will them <hi>heal?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or how can any teach the <hi>Law,</hi> who yet the <hi>Law</hi> do <hi>break,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Such <hi>Teachers</hi> make Gods Name <hi>blaſphemd</hi> when they <hi>preſume to ſpeak</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or how <hi>blind Guides</hi> can lead the <hi>way</hi> in which others ſhould <hi>go,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or any free out of the <hi>Pit,</hi> themſelves do <hi>ſtumble ſo?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So what authority have theſe at all others to <hi>Teach,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>When ſtill the <hi>Law</hi> doth them <hi>condemn,</hi> how can they <hi>Gospel Preach?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Moreover they ſay, <hi>None from ſin, are free here,</hi> thus they tell,</l>
                  <l>So prove themſelves <hi>falſe-witneſſes</hi> of True <hi>Emanuel.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="18" facs="tcp:62159:10"/>
                  <l> And this alſo doth teſtifie, their <hi>labour</hi>'s all in <hi>vain,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So they do give themſelves the <hi>lye,</hi> yet they muſt <hi>preach</hi> for <hi>gain;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Becauſe they have their <hi>time</hi> all ſpent, and thus been exercis'd,</l>
                  <l>Yea this <hi>good Doctrine</hi> counted was, till <hi>Quakers</hi> them ſurpris'd.</l>
                  <l>But if there be a <hi>David</hi> here, whoſe <hi>Table</hi>'s richly ſpread,</l>
                  <l>Whoſe <hi>Cup</hi> doth overflow, he may ſpeak with a <hi>holy dread,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The things he hath ſo learn'd of God, and preach his <hi>holy Word;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But no <hi>Dreamers</hi> we can allow, for them's prepard the <hi>Sword.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Their <hi>Father</hi> and their <hi>Mother</hi> both, the which did them <hi>beget,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>While they <hi>propheſie</hi> ſhall run through, this <hi>Sword</hi> againſt them's <hi>ſet.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Oh this is the <hi>commanding Power</hi> doth fleſh in <hi>ſilence keep,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Their glorious <hi>Dreams</hi> we'll nor admire which are <hi>products</hi> of <hi>ſleep.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For now that <hi>bleſſed hour is come, The dead Gods Voice do hear,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And many that <hi>did ſleep awak:</hi> For Chriſt he <hi>doth appear,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yea from the <hi>dead</hi> they <hi>riſen</hi> are, and Chriſt hath gi'n them <hi>Light,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſin reprov'd, in which we walkt in darkneſs of the <hi>Night;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And unto <hi>Judgement</hi> we are come, which <hi>Sion</hi> doth <hi>redeem,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>With <hi>Righteouſneſs</hi> his <hi>Converts</hi> he, doth bring unto <hi>eſteem.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For that all <hi>Judgement</hi> to the <hi>Son,</hi> the <hi>Father</hi> doth commit,</l>
                  <l>And now to <hi>Judgement</hi> he is come, and in <hi>mens hearts</hi> doth ſit;</l>
                  <l>And all his <hi>Enemies</hi> that will not have the <hi>Lord to raign,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Before his face they are brought forth, with order <hi>to be ſlain.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The ſtrong man he doth alſo <hi>bind,</hi> that did his own <hi>Houſe keep,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And <hi>ſpoil</hi> of all his <hi>Goods</hi> hath made, now the <hi>Soul's wake</hi> from <hi>ſleep.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For now our <hi>God</hi> he doth <hi>ariſe,</hi> his <hi>enemies</hi> to <hi>ſcatter,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Which are theſe <hi>dreaming Prophets</hi> that, do thus <hi>fawn, lye</hi> and <hi>flatter,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And being in his <hi>own Houſe</hi> doth his <hi>Oracles</hi> ſpeak now,</l>
                  <l>So this ſame ſence of <hi>Spirit</hi> in all, cannot but it allow.</l>
                  <l>For he that to the Lord is <hi>joynd,</hi> is with him <hi>one in Spirit,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And to this Truth he ſets his <hi>Seal, This gift is no mans Merit.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So by the mouth of ſuch a man, the Lord this uſe doth make,</l>
                  <l>His <hi>holy Word</hi> ſtill to <hi>declare,</hi> as he by <hi>Prophets</hi> ſpake.</l>
                  <l>For ſuch a man, he can <hi>declare</hi> the things that he hath <hi>ſeen,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And <hi>ears</hi> have <hi>heard,</hi> for with his <hi>hands Gods Word</hi> hath <hi>handled</hi> been.</l>
                  <l>Yea this is he can truly tell you things of <hi>admiration,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>What for his Soul the Lord hath done in his <hi>Regeneration.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So he is gatherd up into the <hi>Cloud of Witneſſes,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Which here alone did <hi>ſerve</hi> the Lord, yea him did <hi>fear</hi> and <hi>pleaſe.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And theſe are they that do not <hi>preach</hi> at any time for <hi>Hire,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But having <hi>Gods Word</hi> in their heart, cannot contain; <hi>Tis fire.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="19" facs="tcp:62159:10"/>
                  <l> And if the <hi>Holy Ghoſt</hi> could not for <hi>money</hi> then he bought,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Simon Magus</hi> was condemn'd for having ſuch a thought,</l>
                  <l>What is the <hi>Ghoſt</hi> that is in men, that money out do reach,</l>
                  <l>And what is that which it receives with condition to preach?</l>
                  <l>It ſeemeth then, that they have not of God this ſelf-ſame <hi>Gift,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Sith that they can contain themſelves, till we for money ſhift</l>
                  <l>For them, their <hi>lips</hi> can <hi>knowledge keep,</hi> ther's <hi>none that they wil cheriſh</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For if <hi>People no money have,</hi> they all are like to <hi>periſh:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For <hi>freely</hi> they <hi>receiv'd</hi> have not, the <hi>Goſpel</hi> they do <hi>preach.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And therefore <hi>freely</hi> can't it <hi>give,</hi> ſo for <hi>rewards</hi> do <hi>Teach.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That theſe men truly you may know, they tell you what was ſaid</l>
                  <l>By <hi>Prophets, Chriſt,</hi> and <hi>Apoſtels,</hi> theſe are their only aid.</l>
                  <l>And thus like to the <hi>wandring Jews,</hi> in their Names would <hi>caſt out</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>unclean ſpirit</hi> that's in men, but it gives them the <hi>rout;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſo upon them <hi>it doth fall,</hi> that they do <hi>quarter crave,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And do return and tell men that, <hi>him out there's none can have:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For that they know they <hi>Power have,</hi> both <hi>in</hi> and <hi>or'e</hi> them to,</l>
                  <l>Though they uſe <hi>Paul</hi> and <hi>Jeſus words,</hi> for <hi>money</hi> this they do.</l>
                  <l>For <hi>Satans Kingdom</hi>'s not ſo weak, he ſhould himſelf out caſt,</l>
                  <l>But this ſame <hi>preaching Pollicy,</hi> makes it the longer laſt.</l>
                  <l>And ſo he ſets them for to ſteal, the <hi>Saints</hi> and <hi>Prophets Words.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And bids them hear the <hi>Word of God,</hi> thus much he them affords:</l>
                  <l>But yet with this <hi>Proviſo</hi> to, <hi>That none the ſame can keep,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or any now hath the <hi>ſame Spirit,</hi> but that it ſtill doth ſleep:</l>
                  <l>And therefore muſt not now look for any ſuch <hi>Miracle,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For the <hi>power</hi> and <hi>work</hi> is loſt, this is <hi>Satans Oracle.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For he hath now changed his <hi>Form,</hi> to keep from <hi>Peoples ſight,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Though he <hi>the Prince of darkneſs be,</hi> yet ſeems <hi>Angel of Light.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Theſe <hi>Prieſts</hi> and <hi>Curats</hi> that do take upon them <hi>Souls to cure,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Phyſitians</hi> are <hi>of no value,</hi> that God's fire can't endure.</l>
                  <l>But here you ſee they have but what they from their <hi>Neighbours ſteal</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>They having not <hi>ſet Seal to God,</hi> he nought to them <hi>reveals.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And though they ſay, <hi>Hear you Gods Word, ſpoken</hi> to <hi>Jeremy,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or unto ſome other <hi>Prophet,</hi> yet in their <hi>mouth's a lye.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſo tho they do <hi>ſay</hi> or <hi>ſwear,</hi> that the <hi>Lord he doth <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yea then they do <hi>falſe witneſs bear,</hi> this <hi>Test they cannot give.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Whereas thoſe that do <hi>dwell</hi> in <hi>God,</hi> and <hi>He dwelleth in them,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>Prophets</hi> and <hi>Apoſtles know,</hi> yea <hi>Davids <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> and <hi>Stone.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>B<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>ing in the <hi>Path they walkt,</hi> do ſee, <hi>their foot-ſteps every one,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And know their <hi>Light</hi> and <hi>Lanthorn to,</hi> which unto <hi>them hath ſhown,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="20" facs="tcp:62159:11"/>
                  <l> And therefore can in truth <hi>repeat,</hi> what they to all do tell,</l>
                  <l>That God alſo their <hi>Souls</hi> hath brought from the <hi>dark pit of Hell</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This <hi>Spirit</hi> it may <hi>Preach</hi> and <hi>Teach,</hi> Gods <hi>wonders</hi> manifold,</l>
                  <l>The which can <hi>ſpeak</hi> Gods <hi>Word</hi> in truth, being right, a <hi>Lyin bol<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Here you may ſee we do not <hi>quench</hi> Gods <hi>Spirit</hi> he affords,</l>
                  <l>That in the leaſt meaſure doth <hi>ſpeak,</hi> rejoyce we at thoſe <hi>words.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>Something about SILENCE.</head>
               <lg>
                  <head>Object.</head>
                  <l>BUT ſome do ſay, <hi>We marvel much, that you can ſit</hi> Silent,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>We do conceive it no profit, nor are with it content;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For if that we ſhould ſit a while, ſilent from hearing breath,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Our mind a wandring then would be up and down in the Earth:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And ſo contriving in our hearts, whats to be done, we plot</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Till there be ſometing we know not that on our heart doth ſmote:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And if this earthly ſpirit act <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>n, for which we feel this ſmart,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Some former evil we have done, lyes gnawing of our heart.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>So to this outward Ear we muſt have Objects that do ſound,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>That the inward</hi> Intelect <hi>may, thereby be wholly drown'd:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For that which doth us thus reprove, and on our hearts doth ſmite,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Doth</hi> ſilence <hi>make our burthen, 'cauſe it brings that to our ſight:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For this is that to us doth ſhew, the evils we have done,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>In</hi> ſilence <hi>we are made to know, therefore we</hi> ſilence <hi>ſhun.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And ſo among the trees do run, our ſelves there for to hide,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For this ſame ſmall</hi> ſtill Voice, <hi>at all, by no means we abide.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Anſwer.</head>
                  <l>All this we muſt confeſs alſo, for we the ſame have felt,</l>
                  <l>Gods Loving-kindneſs we do know, thus he with us have dealt;</l>
                  <l>For tis the Lord the which doth <hi>wound,</hi> and he doth alſo <hi>heal,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>'Tis he doth <hi>kill</hi> and make <hi>alive,</hi> thus with us he doth <hi>deal:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>All the <hi>Satanick thoughts</hi> which thus wandred within our hearts,</l>
                  <l>His <hi>Light</hi> and <hi>Power</hi> did reprove; he caſt at them his <hi>Darts.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="21" facs="tcp:62159:11"/>
                  <l> For this is the true Prophet which <hi>Ahab</hi> cannot abide,</l>
                  <l>That Propheſies not well of him, that from the Lord doth ſlide;</l>
                  <l>And this is the Prophet alſo, that the <hi>Samarians</hi> knew,</l>
                  <l>Which told them all they ever did; they ſaid 'Twas Chriſt the true:</l>
                  <l>Though he at that time was in <hi>Feſh,</hi> when he their thoughts did <hi>ſhow,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But now in <hi>Spirit</hi> again is come, by theſe things we him <hi>know.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>Word</hi> which in <hi>beginning was made Feſh, Chriſt,</hi> yeſterday,</l>
                  <l>The <hi>ſame is now,</hi> and <hi>e're ſhall be,</hi> true Soules <hi>Eternal ſtay.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And this is that muſt humble all, it is Gods <hi>mighty hand,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Before that ye exalted be his <hi>Power</hi> muſt make you ſtand.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And therefore now to <hi>Silence come,</hi> Chaſtiſement do'nt refuſe,</l>
                  <l>For 'tis Gods <hi>Love</hi> unto you all, his Sons hereby doth chuſe.</l>
                  <l>And therefore now with <hi>David</hi> pray the Lord your <hi>hearts to ſearch,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>To find out all <hi>Iniquity,</hi> and in his <hi>fire it parch.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yea with thy Candle do thou Lord, ſearch thy <hi>Jeruſalem,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Tha it thy <hi>Holy City</hi> may, be when thou turn'ſt out them,</l>
                  <l>That have kept and defil'd thy <hi>Houſe,</hi> the <hi>Temple</hi> that is thine,</l>
                  <l>Which unto thee ſhould holy be; Deſtroy them all in time</l>
                  <l>That are not <hi>Children</hi> of thy <hi>Houſe,</hi> but came in by the <hi>Fall:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This Heathen <hi>Babyloniſh brood,</hi> daſh them againſt the <hi>Wall.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This <hi>Enemy</hi> which in thy <hi>Field,</hi> when men ſlept there did <hi>Sow,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>His <hi>Legions</hi> of <hi>Tares,</hi> O Lord, let them thy <hi>fire know.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This <hi>Man of ſin</hi> in thy <hi>Temple,</hi> preſumptuouſly doth ſit,</l>
                  <l>Exalting of himſelf above all that is calld <hi>God</hi> yet;</l>
                  <l>And ſhewing of himſelf to be, the <hi>God of all the Earth,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Giving forth Laws of ſin and death, to all that here have breath.</l>
                  <l>And by thoſe Laws in Members war, and doth us captive lead,</l>
                  <l>Therefore for us, <hi>O mighty God,</hi> our Cauſe now do thou plead.</l>
                  <l>For in Hea'n we have none but Thee, nor in Earth do we ſeek;</l>
                  <l>For any other helper but <hi>Thou Lamb of God,</hi> the <hi>Meek.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For this ſame mighty <hi>Man of ſin,</hi> ſends Miniſters to praech,</l>
                  <l>None can be freed from <hi>ſin</hi> or <hi>death,</hi> this Doctrine they do preach.</l>
                  <l>Whereby we all our Life-time have, been kept in miſery,</l>
                  <l>They alſo boldly do affirm, that <hi>Paul</hi> he then did lye;</l>
                  <l>When unto God he did give thanks, which was his <hi>ſtrength</hi> and <hi>ſtay,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For that he had <hi>deliverance,</hi> through Jeſus Chriſt, <hi>the Way.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And though <hi>Paul</hi> in his Agony, did ask the queſtion ſo,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>From this Body of ſin and death, Who ſhall deliver? Who?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This <hi>queſtion</hi> it was only writ 'cauſe he would <hi>anſwer</hi> make,</l>
                  <l>Who was the alone <hi>Deliverance,</hi> and for whoſe onely ſake.</l>
                  <pb n="22" facs="tcp:62159:12"/>
                  <l> For none ſuch tender pitty had to the <hi>poor wretched man,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>To bind his <hi>wounds,</hi> and's wants <hi>ſupply,</hi> but th' <hi>good Samaritan;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Who <hi>poured oyl into his wounds,</hi> ſet him on <hi>his own Beaſt,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And brought him unto <hi>Chriſts own Inne,</hi> the place of <hi>all Souls Reſt;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>With <hi>Wounds bound up,</hi> and <hi>Charges paid,</hi> this <hi>Love the Lord doth ſend</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>With <hi>Stock laid in for future time,</hi> what the poor <hi>Soul ſhould ſpend.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Now ſhall not <hi>Paul</hi> when he is <hi>cleans'd,</hi> and other <hi>Leapers</hi> to,</l>
                  <l>Return and give to God the <hi>thanks,</hi> to whom alone tis due.</l>
                  <l>With <hi>David</hi> alſo come and tell, <hi>what for his ſoul is done,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And that <hi>no Condemnation is,</hi> in <hi>Jeſus Christ, Gods Son.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For they now <hi>walk not after fleſh,</hi> another <hi>Law they have,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The which of <hi>Spirit</hi> is and <hi>Life,</hi> that doth <hi>their poor Souls ſave;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And this doth alſo <hi>ſet them free,</hi> from <hi>Fleſh, Law, Sin</hi> and <hi>Death,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And makes <hi>dry Bones together come,</hi> for <hi>God ſends for his Breath.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Which is the <hi>Goſpel-Power</hi> of God, which <hi>thoſe Miniſters hide,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Whoſe minds the <hi>God of this World blinds,</hi> leſt he ſhould be <hi>eſpide.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thus they go forth and People tell, <hi>from ſin they can't be freed,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Whilſt on this ſide the Grave we are;</hi> So their <hi>Lord's Lord</hi> indeed.</l>
                  <l>So making void the <hi>mighty Power,</hi> of the <hi>Emanuel,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Who came <hi>to ſave People from ſin,</hi> Lyes of him they do tell:</l>
                  <l>As if <hi>his Hand were ſhortned,</hi> and <hi>weakned were his Power.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or that the <hi>World</hi> the <hi>Divels</hi> were, for to <hi>rule every hour.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Whereas <hi>all Power in Heaven and Earth unto the Son is given,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And he muſt ſurely <hi>Raign on Earth,</hi> though's <hi>Enemies have ſtriven,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Him to oppoſe;</hi> yet, if not <hi>here, Oh where ſhall Gods Son Raign?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For <hi>all his Enemies, Death and Hell, ſhall every one be ſlain:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For he muſt Rule till theſe be brought under his feet, then ſhall,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>The Son his Kingdom re-aſſigne, and God be all in all.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>So ſtop your mouths you <hi>Meſſengers</hi> that are <hi>Satanical,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For the <hi>Lords Chriſt</hi> is come to <hi>Raign,</hi> his <hi>Rule muſt be</hi> your <hi>Fall;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And all your <hi>mighty Captains</hi> to, which are of <hi>his Empire,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For <hi>Dragon, Beaſt, Falſe Prophet</hi> to, ſhall be caſt in the <hi>fire.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For the <hi>Lords Christ</hi> came to deſtroy <hi>all the works of the Devil,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That <hi>Righteouſneſs E'relasting may,</hi> be brought from <hi>all that's evil,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And if he were not to <hi>deſtroy</hi> his works in this <hi>world wrought,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>What other <hi>World</hi> doth he <hi>work in,</hi> that any out <hi>have ſought?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>When he his <hi>Meſſengers</hi> and <hi>Works,</hi> are all <hi>cast in the fire,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>What <hi>Works can he,</hi> or <hi>they then do,</hi> that any can <hi>deſire?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>'Tis alſo in <hi>this wicked World,</hi> Gods Grace <hi>Salvation brings,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Teaching us <hi>worldly Luſts to ſhun,</hi> and each <hi>ungoly thing.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="23" facs="tcp:62159:12"/>
                  <l> And in this <hi>preſent world to live godly and ſoberly,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And to relieve in <hi>Righteouſneſs</hi> the <hi>fatherleſs thereby.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>Widow</hi> likewiſe to <hi>viſit,</hi> this is <hi>Religion pure,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>From the <hi>Worlds ſpots</hi> thus to keep clear, the <hi>Devil can't endure.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And if all this you can't <hi>believe,</hi> take your own <hi>evidence,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Of your <hi>own Doctrine</hi> the <hi>reſult,</hi> and <hi>Catachiſtick ſence.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Whereby this Truth it is confirm'd, 'gainſt all to be the ſame,</l>
                  <l>Where Children they are taught to ſay, whats <hi>promis'd in their name</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>That the Devil and AL his works, they must and will forſake,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And AL the Pomps and Vanities of this world leave to take;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And AL the ſinful Luſts alſo, of the Fleſh,</hi> which do riſe,</l>
                  <l>ALL theſe they muſt be now <hi>forſook,</hi> that did their hearts ſurprize,</l>
                  <l>And theſe not only to be left, but <hi>they Gods Word muſt keep,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And his holy Commandements, all their Life,</hi> not in ſleep</l>
                  <l>This <hi>Chriſtian Article of Faith,</hi> they muſt fully <hi>believe,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Though they themſelves their <hi>works deſtroy,</hi> yet this to <hi>learn they give</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Oh is no here <hi>Babel built now, anon pull'd down again,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This is the <hi>Dialect</hi> they ſpeal, of <hi>Sounds</hi> this is the <hi>ſtrain.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Object.</head>
                  <l>But ſome may ſay, <hi>For all this yet,</hi> Paul <hi>in his fleſh did feel,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>A Prick Buffeting of Satan, and this God did not heal.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Anſw.</head>
                  <l>All this is true in his <hi>Warfare, Pricks</hi> in the fleſh he may,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Buffetings</hi> of <hi>Satan</hi> to, who ſought him to deſtroy.</l>
                  <l>For when that <gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e a <hi>Souldier was, of Satan,</hi> on his ſide,</l>
                  <l>He then <hi>with might did Perſecute, Christians could not abide.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And like his <hi>Maſter went about, roaring for to devour,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And Letters had from the <hi>High Priest,</hi> to take all in his <hi>Power.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſaid himſelf, <hi>He was e'en mad, 'gainſt</hi> all on God did call,</l>
                  <l>He <hi>went from houſe to houſe</hi> and did, them <hi>unto Priſon hall.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Now all this time there was no cauſe <hi>Satan ſhould buffet</hi> Saul,</l>
                  <l>Till that he had his <hi>Champion loſt, and was convert to</hi> Paul.</l>
                  <l>And now who otherwiſe can think, but <hi>Paul bufft'ed muſt be,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>by his old <hi>Maſter</hi> that he ſerv'd, now they do not agree.</l>
                  <l>Moreover muſt not <hi>Paul now have</hi> the <hi>meaſure he hid give,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And now the <hi>Wheel's upon him turn'd,</hi> till the Lord him <hi>relieve.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="24" facs="tcp:62159:13"/>
                  <l> So this no evil was in <hi>Paul,</hi> nor ought that was unjuſt,</l>
                  <l>Though to the Lord he three times ſought, 'cauſe he did <hi>on him truſt.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This ſeeking to the Lord did ſhew, who had the power and might,</l>
                  <l>And that himſelf was but weakneſs, 'twas <hi>God</hi> muſt for him fight.</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Anſwer</hi> was he ſhould not <hi>Fear, ſufficient was his Grace,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Him to defend, and Courage give, his Enemies to face.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>He now muſt be a <hi>Souldier for,</hi> his <hi>new Maſter,</hi> tis right,</l>
                  <l>Therefore with <hi>Pricks</hi> and <hi>Buffets to,</hi> his <hi>old Maſter</hi> doth fight,</l>
                  <l>Againſt him in temptation, in raiſing of his mind,</l>
                  <l>To glory in the things he ſaw, to which before he's blind.</l>
                  <l>But by the <hi>Shield</hi> of <hi>Faith</hi> he did defend himſelf from <hi>evil,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And <hi>quenched hath</hi> the <hi>fiery darts,</hi> caſt at him from the <hi>Devil.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And Gods <hi>Light Armour</hi> on he put, with the <hi>Sword of the Spirit,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>Helmet of Salvation</hi> to, all's <hi>Free,</hi> here is no <hi>Merit.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So with this <hi>Armour</hi> and <hi>Weapon, Paul</hi> did <hi>fight a good fight,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Againſt the <hi>Devil, kept the Faith,</hi> by Gods <hi>Pow-er</hi> and <hi>Might.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And by this <hi>Faith</hi> he did reſiſt the <hi>Devil</hi> and made him <hi>fly,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And in this <hi>Faith</hi> the <hi>Victory got,</hi> alſo a <hi>Crown</hi> thereby.</l>
                  <l>The which the Righteous God will give unto his <hi>Souldiers</hi> all,</l>
                  <l>That under this his <hi>Banner fight,</hi> and on his <hi>Name do call.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So all may ſee that this was not <hi>an evil</hi> then in <hi>Paul,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But <hi>Souldiers marks</hi> of <hi>Jeſus Christ,</hi> the which we muſt bear all.</l>
                  <l>And his ſeeking thus unto God, is as a <hi>ſucking Child,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That ſeeketh for its <hi>Mothers Breaſt,</hi> that is <hi>tender</hi> and <hi>mild.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And when the <hi>Child</hi> had <hi>ſuckt</hi> its fill, the <hi>Breast</hi> likewiſe is eas'd,</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Child</hi> then it is ſatisfi'd, and <hi>Mother</hi> alſo pleas'd.</l>
                  <l>This <hi>figure</hi> God made uſe of when, to <hi>Iſrael</hi> he did ſay,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Her Child, can a Mother forget, that ſucks on her each day?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This is the <hi>Faith</hi> that <hi>ſucks</hi> the <hi>Breaſt</hi> of <hi>Conſolation,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>By which the <hi>Just</hi> ſhall ever live if they feed thereupon.</l>
                  <l>For in the World we are but ſent, this plainly doth appear,</l>
                  <l>Which ſhews our <hi>Father is alive,</hi> in whoſe <hi>Houſe</hi> is our chear,</l>
                  <l>In which is <hi>Bread of Life</hi> enough, and <hi>Manſions</hi> there are many,</l>
                  <l>So <hi>Prodigals</hi> muſt come thereto, if they mean to have any.</l>
                  <l>And this may well obſerved be, what doth the <hi>Father</hi> move,</l>
                  <l>No ſooner ſees his <hi>Son</hi> to come, but <hi>R<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>NS</hi> to meet his <hi>Love.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Oh here is <hi>Love, Love, Love indeed,</hi> Who can ſuch <hi>Love</hi> er'e <hi>ſhun,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For when <hi>poor Souls</hi> begin to <hi>move,</hi> the <hi>Father</hi> he doth <hi>R<g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>N;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yea not <hi>away,</hi> but <hi>towards</hi> him, as if it were a <hi>Bliſs,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>With arms ſpread out doth it receive, and gives to it a <hi>Kiſs.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="25" facs="tcp:62159:13"/>
                  <l> And is not only here content, with joy his Houſe doth ſound,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Becauſe the dead is made alive, his loſt Son now is found.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſeemeth to be <hi>ſervile</hi> to, beſet with <hi>cares</hi> and <hi>fears,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Waiting for to be <hi>garcious,</hi> on <hi>Iſrael forty years,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And when that we did <hi>wallow in the blood</hi> that was our own,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>
                        <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nſalted, waſht</hi> or <hi>pittied,</hi> then was his <hi>ſtrong Arm known.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Oh this was Gods own only <hi>Power,</hi> that did <hi>Salvation</hi> bring,</l>
                  <l>Oh this was then a time of <hi>Love,</hi> which makes us now to ſing;</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Salvation, Glory</hi> and <hi>Power,</hi> unto our God for ever,</l>
                  <l>Who is our preſent help at hand, his <hi>Promiſe</hi> faild us never.</l>
                  <l>So all may ſee the ground-work then that ſolely doth us move</l>
                  <l>In our affections to <hi>Love him,</hi> 'cauſe <hi>firſt he did us Love,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For when that we <hi>ungodly were,</hi> then he <hi>his own Son ſent,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>From <hi>ſin</hi> and <hi>Satan</hi> us to <hi>free,</hi> this was his <hi>true intent.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>From <hi>Egypts darkneſs,</hi> and <hi>Deaths bonds,</hi> poor Souls he did <hi>ſet free,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This was Gods <hi>Love,</hi> and the Sons <hi>Word,</hi> in this both did <hi>agree.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This <hi>Truth</hi> alſo in many things, illuſtrated may be,</l>
                  <l>That we no <hi>Independants</hi> are, alone on God live we.</l>
                  <l>Though we as ſtrong as <hi>Sampſon</hi> were, who the <hi>Philiſtines</hi> killd,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>heaps on heaps</hi> of them did bear, yet he to <hi>Death</hi> muſt yeild,</l>
                  <l>Till the Lord cleave a hollow place, where water did ſpring out,</l>
                  <l>In the ſame <hi>Jaw-bone</hi> of the <hi>Aſſe,</hi> wherewith he made the <hi>Rout,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And when that he had drank thereof his Spirit came again,</l>
                  <l>And he revived alſo was, though given himſelf as ſlain;</l>
                  <l>So of our ſelves no <hi>ſtrength</hi> we have, 'tis in God we muſt hoaſt,</l>
                  <l>Who is our <hi>Captain, Strength</hi> and <hi>Stay,</hi> the <hi>only Lord of Hoaſts.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Now by <hi>experience David may,</hi> (yet in Gods ſtrength alone)</l>
                  <l>Declare how he by it had killd, the great <hi>Philiſtian;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>Lyon, Bear,</hi> and through an <hi>Hoaſt</hi> gone by this ſtrength he hath,</l>
                  <l>And he <hi>over a Wall hath lept,</hi> that ſtood a croſs his <hi>Path.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This is the way that he did go, and therefore <hi>Courage</hi> took,</l>
                  <l>'Cauſe formerly God did him help, and never him forſook.</l>
                  <l>Though then were ſome, as there be now, which unto him did ſay,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>That in his God no help there was, whereon his ſoul to ſtay.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This plainly then, you now may ſee, theſe cauſe <hi>mens hearts to faint,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Denying of Gods ſtrength, which he doth work in every <hi>Saint.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So putting them quite out of heart, for ever to attain,</l>
                  <l>Over their <hi>hearts-luſts Victory</hi> or <hi>Ground</hi> on them to gain</l>
                  <l>This Spirit you may alſo ſee, in <hi>Iſrael</hi> of old,</l>
                  <l>Which did not the true <hi>Spies</hi> believe, though they God; <hi>Truth b<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap> told</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="26" facs="tcp:62159:14"/>
                  <l> For they the Sons of <hi>Anack</hi> feard, that <hi>mighty</hi> were and <hi>tall,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So did not in <hi>Gods Power truſt,</hi> but fell a <hi>murmuring</hi> all;</l>
                  <l>And their falſe <hi>Spies</hi> to help forward their <hi>unbelief</hi> and <hi>ſpight,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Said, <hi>They appear'd like Graſhoppers in the</hi> Anakims <hi>ſight.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>None doubted then, nor do they now, <hi>but the Land it is good,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But how't could then, or now can be <hi>attaind,</hi> the <hi>Queſtion</hi> ſtood?</l>
                  <l>And notwithſtanding God to them ſuch <hi>Miracles</hi> did ſhow,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>wonderfully</hi> brought them out of <hi>Egypt,</hi> they did know,</l>
                  <l>Yet thoſe <hi>falſe Spies</hi> did them <hi>perſwade,</hi> as <hi>Miniſters</hi> do now,</l>
                  <l>(Of <hi>Satan</hi> which do make a trade againſt God to avow)</l>
                  <l>That from their <hi>Maſters Kingdom</hi> he, poor <hi>Souls</hi> cannot <hi>ſet free,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or that his <hi>Kingdom</hi> in this World, <hi>diminiſhed</hi> ſhall be.</l>
                  <l>Which is the cauſe of <hi>
                        <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nbelief,</hi> amongſt us now at length,</l>
                  <l>But thoſe that <hi>unto Sion come, do grow from ſtrength to ſtrength.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And now, as then, the <hi>true Caleb,</hi> do ſtill the People tell,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>The Land is good, and to Conquer, they able are full well.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And that the People ſhould not <hi>fear,</hi> unto them thus he <hi>ſed,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Their Defence doth from them depart, they are to us for Bread:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And that <hi>the Lord he was with them, there was no cauſe to fear,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yet they for all this did rebell, for their words did not care.</l>
                  <l>For many <hi>falſe Spies</hi> ſtill they had, which brought an <hi>ill report,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So that the <hi>Congregation,</hi> bad <hi>ſtone them with ſtones</hi> for't.</l>
                  <l>Now if there be a <hi>Caleb</hi> that, God <hi>follow fully</hi> will</l>
                  <l>With <hi>other Spirit</hi> than they do, they cry, <hi>him ſtone, or kill.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And yet for all this God will bring his <hi>Calebs</hi> to this Land,</l>
                  <l>They and their Seed ſhall it poſſeſs, which to his <hi>Truth do ſtand,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Who do <hi>believe</hi> and ſo <hi>confeſs, God by his Power can,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Bring his People out of</hi> Egypt, <hi>to heavenly</hi> Canaan.</l>
                  <l>From this it may obſerved be, <hi>The falſe ſpies they are many,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>From which the ground of <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nbelief doth ſpring: Truth ſcarce hath any.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Though in this work it is their ſhare, to <hi>ſuffer,</hi> as men think,</l>
                  <l>Yet unto us it is our <hi>Joy, of Chriſts own Cup to drink.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>E'en as twas then, ſo it is now, <hi>Deſtructions way is wide,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And <hi>many follow in the ſame,</hi> few from it <hi>turn aſide.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Theſe men that did <hi>Gods glory ſee,</hi> and <hi>miracles</hi> alſo.</l>
                  <l>In <hi>Egypt</hi> and i'th <hi>Wilderneſs,</hi> do tempt him ten times mo</l>
                  <l>Than thoſe that never yet did ſee, <hi>Gods Power,</hi> that's <hi>Divine,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>More tollerable it ſhall be, for ſuch who have no <hi>Sign,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Theſe <hi>Miracles</hi> and <hi>Wonders great, Advantages</hi> ſhould be,</l>
                  <l>And in our hearts ſuch <hi>Courage raiſe,</hi> that we no <hi>fear</hi> ſhould ſee.</l>
                  <pb n="27" facs="tcp:62159:14"/>
                  <l> This is the way <hi>David</hi> did go with confidence to <hi>Saul,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>He took up <hi>Courage</hi> in his heart, and told <hi>Iſrael</hi> all,</l>
                  <l>That in <hi>Gods ſtrength,</hi> a <hi>Lyon</hi> he had killed, and a <hi>Bear,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And therefore this <hi>Phyſitian bold</hi> knew no ſuch thing as <hi>Fear.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This <hi>Plea</hi> we 'gainſt all thoſe have that unto <hi>People preach,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Let God or man do what they can, Man</hi> Canaan <hi>Land can't reach.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <head>Something of the Cauſe of DARKNESSE, IGNORANCE and PERSECUTI<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ON.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>AS the dark Body of the <hi>Moon,</hi> which in the Night is <hi>Light,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That it receiveth from the <hi>Sun,</hi> by ſtanding in its <hi>ſight;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And then again by <hi>Reflection</hi> on us this <hi>Light</hi> doth <hi>caſt,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>While it thus governeth the <hi>Night,</hi> (no longer doth it laſt)</l>
                  <l>For when the <hi>Day-light</hi> doth <hi>appear,</hi> it <hi>wan</hi> doth wax and <hi>fade,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>'Cauſe it retains no <hi>Life,</hi> or <hi>Power,</hi> nor hath it any <hi>Shade;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For that the <hi>brightneſs of the Sun</hi> with its moſt <hi>glorious beams,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>In its large <hi>Womb</hi> hath <hi>ſwallowed up</hi> her <hi>pale</hi> and <hi>glimmering Streams</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>By which he <hi>Body</hi> is made <hi>dark,</hi> this all may plainly ſee;</l>
                  <l>And when it gets before the <hi>Sun,</hi> then an <hi>Eclipſe</hi> will be,</l>
                  <l>Yea this alſo may be minded, becauſe it is moſt clear,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>The Sun is ne're Eclipſed but, when th'</hi> Moon <hi>is in its Sphere.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And the <hi>Earths Body</hi> alſo is as dark as is the <hi>Moon,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For when it gets before the <hi>Sun,</hi> the <hi>Moon</hi>'s <hi>Eclips'd</hi> full ſoon.</l>
                  <l>Thus <hi>Nature</hi> hath theſe outward <hi>Signs</hi> that in their <hi>Sphears do run,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For the <hi>Earths Body</hi> doth <hi>Eclipſe</hi> the <hi>Moon,</hi> and <hi>She</hi> the <hi>Sun.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Theſe outward <hi>Signs</hi> of <hi>Heaven</hi> were diſcern'd by men of old,</l>
                  <l>Who yet the <hi>Myſtery</hi> did not ſee being all led <hi>blind-fold;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Becauſe the <hi>God of this World</hi> had their <hi>minds wholly blinded,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Leſt that the <hi>Gospel-Light ſhould ſhine,</hi> and they by it <hi>be led,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And though the <hi>Hypocrites</hi> of old <hi>Heavens</hi> outward could <hi>diſcern,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yet did not know true <hi>Bethlehem,</hi> where Gods own <hi>Seed was born,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Of theſe <hi>Figures</hi> the <hi>Prophets</hi> did, of old make uſe, you ſee,</l>
                  <l>When they told where the <hi>World</hi> was ſet, in mans heart there to be.</l>
                  <pb n="28" facs="tcp:62159:15"/>
                  <l> So he that to God is a Friend, muſt have the World caſt out,</l>
                  <l>From this ſame place where it is ſet, elſe Truth it will not ſprout.</l>
                  <l>And this the cauſe of the <hi>Eclipſe,</hi> that man comes not to know,</l>
                  <l>Neither beginning nor the end, of him God doth not ſhow;</l>
                  <l>The works that he at all times doth, they being <hi>heavenly,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Becauſe of this total <hi>Eclipſe,</hi> that on his heart doth lye.</l>
                  <l>So that the <hi>Moons</hi> dark <hi>Body</hi>'s of, to us, no uſe at all,</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Sun</hi> reflecting not thereon, by the <hi>Earths</hi> Interval,</l>
                  <l>This made the <hi>Seers</hi> which of old, with ſhame confounded were,</l>
                  <l>For they no <hi>Anſwer</hi> of God had, becauſe they <hi>Preacht</hi> for hire,</l>
                  <l>Yea for money they did <hi>Devine,</hi> and <hi>Judged</hi> for reward,</l>
                  <l>Thus building up <hi>Sion</hi> with blood, no ſight had of the Lord.</l>
                  <l>The dark <hi>Moon</hi> here is turnd to <hi>BLOOD,</hi> tho it pretend to <hi>build,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>glorious Mountain of the Lord,</hi> have hereby <hi>Saints blood ſpill'd.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And yet for all this ſeem to lean themſelves upon the Lord,</l>
                  <l>As if no evil ſhe had done, but in heart did accord.</l>
                  <l>This hard-heart <hi>Earth</hi> was ſtill the ſame, of which the Lord ſo long</l>
                  <l>Complain'd of in the <hi>Wilderneſs,</hi> it grieved him ſo ſtrong.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>To day, to day,</hi> for forty years, oh this was all the noiſe,</l>
                  <l>But their hard hearts they could not hear the ſounding of his voyce?</l>
                  <l>This <hi>Earth,</hi> this <hi>Luſt,</hi> this <hi>Will,</hi> this <hi>Feſh,</hi> they being of one nature,</l>
                  <l>Are thoſe that keep the <hi>glorious beams</hi> from <hi>ſhining on the Creature.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But now the <hi>Day of God</hi> is come, expel thoſe <hi>Miſts</hi> he will,</l>
                  <l>Which do his <hi>Sun-beams</hi> over-caſt, that ſhine would on his ſtill.</l>
                  <l>For though a man have outward eyes, be they never ſo clear,</l>
                  <l>Yet if that <hi>Night</hi> do him oretake, he is little the neer.</l>
                  <l>And as it is in outward Earth, this is the cauſe of Night,</l>
                  <l>Having a Body <hi>thick</hi> and <hi>groſs,</hi> its ſelf hinders the <hi>Light.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This <hi>Judgement</hi> was on th' Prophets which with their <hi>keen Teeth did bite,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>'Gainſt thoſe that put not in their mouths, in <hi>War</hi> prepare to <hi>fight.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Therefore <hi>Night</hi> ſhould be unto them, they ſhall no <hi>Viſion</hi> have,</l>
                  <l>Not ſo much <hi>Light</hi> as to <hi>devine</hi> how they <hi>themſelves</hi> may <hi>ſave,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And down o're them the <hi>Sun</hi> ſhall go, are <hi>Prophets</hi> of that day,</l>
                  <l>Yea <hi>darkneſs</hi> ſhall oretake them all, <hi>who make not God their ſtay.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>They therefore ſhall <hi>cover their Lipps,</hi> for tho they <hi>call</hi> and <hi>cry,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>They ſhall <hi>no anſwer</hi> have from God, 'cauſe in the earth they <hi>lye.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Theſe were alſo the <hi>Belly-gods,</hi> whoſe <hi>glory was their ſhame,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For that they <hi>Earthly things did mind,</hi> and therefore were to blame.</l>
                  <l>And this likewiſe was that alſo, which <hi>Demas did embrace,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Who for this <hi>preſent world</hi> did, forſake both <hi>Truth</hi> and <hi>Grace.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="29" facs="tcp:62159:15"/>
                  <l> Theſe were the <hi>falſe Teachers</hi> of which <hi>Peter</hi> did ſo fore-tell,</l>
                  <l>Should <hi>Hereſies damnable</hi> bring; that ſwift deſtruction fell</l>
                  <l>Upon them in their <hi>great glory,</hi> for that they ſhould <hi>deny,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>Lord, Light, Life,</hi> that thus bought them, ſo in <hi>dark Death ſhall lye.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yea theſe are they through <hi>Avarice,</hi> and <hi>fained words</hi> ſhould make</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Merchandiſe</hi> of the People too, this <hi>darkneſs</hi> they did take.</l>
                  <l>And following theſe <hi>pernitious wayes</hi> is the ſole reaſon why</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Truths way</hi> is evil ſpoken off, to th' <hi>Light</hi> they'l not come nigh.</l>
                  <l>So this is <hi>Moon Eclips'd</hi> you ſee, the <hi>Earth,</hi> and the <hi>hard Heart,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And now before this <hi>Cloud</hi> be gone, theſe things muſt feel the ſmart.</l>
                  <l>For that the <hi>World</hi> and things therein muſt all be burnt with fire,</l>
                  <l>And be removed from his place, in the <hi>Day of Gods ire.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But what is that which doth <hi>Eclipſe</hi> the <hi>Sun?</hi> The <hi>Moon</hi> (I've ſaid)</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>When it is turned into Blood,</hi> then doth it the <hi>Sun</hi> ſhade,</l>
                  <l>And makes his <hi>Body to look black</hi> and <hi>ſhine,</hi> as if it were</l>
                  <l>For all its <hi>great</hi> and <hi>glorious beams,</hi> but a <hi>Sack-cloth</hi> of <hi>hair.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This was the time that <hi>Joel</hi> did propheſie of, and ſay,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>When Sun was dark, then Moon was blood, this ſhould precede Gods day.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And 'twas fulfil'd when the <hi>ſixth-Seal was opened,</hi> for loe</l>
                  <l>A <hi>mighty Earth-quake then was ſeen,</hi> which many well do know,</l>
                  <l>For then the <hi>Stars</hi> of <hi>Heaven</hi> fell unto the <hi>Earth</hi> their place,</l>
                  <l>Becauſe they were untimely <hi>Figgs,</hi> they ſtaid there but a ſpace,</l>
                  <l>For by this mighty <hi>Wind</hi> and <hi>Storm,</hi> which God among them ſent,</l>
                  <l>He ſhook off what untimely was, tho <hi>glorious things</hi> were ment.</l>
                  <l>And now the <hi>Earth</hi> not only doth, but alſo <hi>Heavens,</hi> ſhake,</l>
                  <l>Becauſe Gods <hi>Day</hi> is at the door, they tremble do and quake.</l>
                  <l>For this firſt <hi>Earth</hi> and <hi>Heaven</hi> too, which <hi>Man</hi> could not ſuſtain,</l>
                  <l>Are both together ſhaken now, their Form doth not remain.</l>
                  <l>Therefore this <hi>Heaven</hi> departed is even as it were a <hi>Scrole,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For all their <hi>glorious fained words,</hi> together when tis rowl'd.</l>
                  <l>And every <hi>Mountain</hi> and <hi>Iſland,</hi> which glory in their <hi>graces,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Are by this <hi>Storm</hi> and mighty <hi>Wind,</hi> remov'd out of their <hi>places.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And they that were <hi>Kings</hi> of the <hi>Earth, Great</hi> and <hi>Rich Men</hi> alſo,</l>
                  <l>With chief <hi>Captains</hi> and <hi>mighty Men,</hi> with <hi>Bond</hi> and <hi>Free-Men</hi> go,</l>
                  <l>And hide themſelves within the <hi>Dens,</hi> yea on the <hi>Mountains</hi> call,</l>
                  <l>And on the <hi>Rocks</hi> for to hide them, or upon them to fall.</l>
                  <l>Theſe are the <hi>Presbyterian Moon,</hi> which in the <hi>Night</hi> was <hi>Light,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But when to <hi>Perſecution</hi> fell, then all was <hi>Blood</hi> and <hi>ſpight;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But now their Kingdom ſhaken is, and they are made to quake,</l>
                  <l>Having their <hi>Meaſure meaſured back,</hi> this makes their <hi>own hearts ak<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                           <desc>•</desc>
                        </gap>.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="30" facs="tcp:62159:16"/>
                  <l> This makes their <hi>Stars,</hi> their <hi>mighty Men,</hi> down from their heaven <hi>fall,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Rather than they will <hi>drink this Cup,</hi> that is <hi>mixed with gall,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſo what <hi>Antichriſtian was</hi> in <hi>Way</hi> and <hi>Form</hi> before,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Covenanted</hi> then <hi>againſt,</hi> the ſame they now <hi>Adore.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thus now their <hi>Valiant Captains</hi> do from <hi>Heaven</hi> daily <hi>ſlide,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Their <hi>Rich</hi> and <hi>mighty Men</hi> alſo, in <hi>Rocks</hi> and <hi>Mountains</hi> hide,</l>
                  <l>From the <hi>Light Face of him that ſits upon his Fathers Throne,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And from <hi>the Wrath of the Lamb</hi> which, they often made to grone.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Object.</head>
                  <l>But ſome may now <hi>Object</hi> and ſay, <hi>This is not fairly done,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>To rip up this our miſery, in the ſight of the Sun,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And as it were for to rejoyce, or'e us in this our fall,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Nor do you put a helping hand to any of us all.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Anſw.</head>
                  <l>To this I <hi>Anſwer,</hi> It is juſt, the <hi>meaſure is your own,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For the <hi>Saints blood ſome of you drank,</hi> as lately hath been ſhown;</l>
                  <l>Your <hi>mighty men</hi> but lately were <hi>Merchants of Babylon,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And dealt in <hi>Slaves</hi> and <hi>Souls of men,</hi> Alas! your <hi>City's gon.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For tho in <hi>Scarlet deckt with Gold, with pretious Stones, and Pearls,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And in <hi>Fine Linnen cloathed were, and lived then like Earls,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yet now your <hi>Ships</hi> and <hi>Companies,</hi> of <hi>Sailers</hi> which did <hi>Trade.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Within the <hi>Sea of Babylon,</hi> did <hi>weep,</hi> and <hi>wail,</hi> and ſaid,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Alas! alas! that great City, wherein we rich were made,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Is like a Mill-ſtone caſt i'th Sea, thus God doth us degrade.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Wherefore, O <hi>Heaven,</hi> or'e her <hi>rejoyce,</hi> ye <hi>Prophets</hi> alſo too,</l>
                  <l>With the <hi>Apoſtels,</hi> for God hath, on <hi>her revenged you.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And your <hi>Crafts men</hi> with all their <hi>Craft,</hi> no more in her <hi>be found,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Nor yet at all ſhall there be <hi>heard,</hi> a <hi>Mill-ſtone</hi> for to <hi>ſound.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thy <hi>Candle-light</hi> for evermore, <hi>exſtinguiſhed</hi> ſhall be,</l>
                  <l>The <hi>voice of Bridegroom</hi> and <hi>of Bride,</hi> be heard <hi>no more in thee.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For that thy <hi>Merchants</hi> they ſtill were, the <hi>Great Men of the Earth</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Which by their <hi>Sorceries deceiv'd</hi> all <hi>Nations</hi> of their <hi>Breath.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For that in her was found <hi>the Blood,</hi> of <hi>Prophets</hi> and of <hi>Saints,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And all that were <hi>ſlain on the Earth,</hi> which brings on her <hi>heart-faints.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Therefore we which in <hi>Heaven dwell,</hi> with <hi>voice,</hi> and <hi>one accord,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Continual <hi>Halilujas</hi> ſing, <hi>Salvation</hi> to the <hi>Lord.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="31" facs="tcp:62159:16"/>
                  <l> With <hi>Glory, Honour,</hi> and <hi>Power</hi> let's praiſe the <hi>Lord of Heaven,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Whoſe <hi>Judgements juſt and righteous</hi> be, he to <hi>the Whore</hi> hath <hi>given;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For why, ſhe did <hi>corrupt the Earth</hi> with her <hi>vile Fornication,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Gods <hi>Servants blood for Vengeance cryes on her abomination.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Now <hi>blood unto her</hi> God hath given, for that it is her <hi>ſhare,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yea <hi>ſhe is worthy of the ſame,</hi> 'cauſe <hi>Saints blood</hi> ſhe'd not <hi>ſpare.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Object.</head>
                  <l>But ſome may ſay, <hi>Why do you thus apply theſe things to them,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>When you alſo now Sufferers are which come of</hi> Jeſſes <hi>Stem?</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Anſw.</head>
                  <l>For <hi>Anſwer,</hi> though we may be <hi>ſlain,</hi> for the good <hi>Word of God,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And for the <hi>Teſtimony</hi> held which we have from the <hi>Lord,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>As thoſe <hi>Souls under th' Altar which, unto the Lord did cry,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For <hi>Vengance on thoſe dwelt on Earth:</hi> and anſwer'd, <hi>Ye muſt lye</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>
                        <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ntil the reſt of your fellow-ſervants and Brethren to,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which witneſſe bear unto my Name, be kill'd as well as you.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For thus 'twas under the <hi>fifth Seal,</hi> the <hi>Angel open'd</hi> when</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Moon was blood,</hi> the <hi>Stars did fall,</hi> and <hi>Sun was hid from men.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>What from the <hi>Earth</hi> can we expect, when <hi>Blood's</hi> the <hi>light of heaven,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But <hi>Perſecution</hi> with effect, when <hi>Stars</hi> to it fall even.</l>
                  <l>But by the way Obſerve, <hi>under the Altar Souls do lye,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The which the <hi>Sacrificer kills,</hi> and there he doth them <hi>tye.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſo <hi>Obedience</hi> was loſt, which was <hi>better than any</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Of all the <hi>Sacrifice</hi> they made, though offer they did many.</l>
                  <l>For their <hi>Oblations</hi> they were <hi>vain, Incenſe abomination,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Nor did God this require of them, they being <hi>Sodoms Nation.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>When they ſpread forth their hands to God, he faſt did cloſe his eyes,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And though they many Prayers made, God did them all despiſe.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Their New Moons and their ſolemn Feaſts, Aſſemblies like a flood,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>The Lord had no regard to 'cauſe their hands were full of Blood.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>It was <hi>Jeruſalem</hi> alſo, that did the <hi>Prophets kill,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſtoned thoſe to them were ſent, and with <hi>blood</hi> did fulfil.</l>
                  <l>And though they ſaid, <hi>they would not be partakers with their Fathers,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>In this ſame <hi>bloody Tragedy,</hi> yet Saints blood they ſtill gather.</l>
                  <l>But deſolate there Houſe is left, Gods <hi>Glory from it's gone,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For that they have <hi>contemnd</hi> the <hi>Sun</hi> which on their <hi>Moon</hi> hath <hi>ſhone.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="32" facs="tcp:62159:17"/>
                  <l> Wherefore they ſhall not henceforth ſee the <hi>true Light</hi> till they ſay,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Bleſſed is he that cometh in the Lord Gods Name alway.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Object.</head>
                  <l>But ſome of theſe <hi>Objected</hi> have againſt us, ſaying, we</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Have not ſo much gain-ſaid, oppos'd, thoſe in our places be,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>So that we cannot chooſe but think you very flatterers are,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And as the common Proverb is,</hi> Your Friends at Court you ſpare;</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For that it hath obſerved been, the men moſt godly were,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Their Congregations you did haunt, and 'gainſt them rave and tear.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>As then, ſo now, thoſe that are bad, 'gainſt them no word doth ſpring,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>But thoſe that zealous were and good, you made their Churches ring.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>So that we cannot but ſuppoſe, the Bottom doth deſign,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Some</hi> Machavillian Policy, <hi>to be acted in time.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And if that this be nothing ſo, why do you not ſtill go</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Into thoſe great Aſſemblies now, the Reaſon let us know.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Anſwer.</head>
                  <l>For <hi>Anſwer</hi> hereunto I ſay, What man is there ſo mad</l>
                  <l>To ſpend his time in the <hi>threſhing of Buſhes?</hi> They'r as bad.</l>
                  <l>For if one would go <hi>vilifie,</hi> the worſt of men there's nought</l>
                  <l>In them (to uſe the <hi>Proverb</hi> old) <hi>that worth a Ruſh is thought.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or who is he that will look for, <hi>Grapes on the thorny Twiggs,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or is there any one that doth <hi>of Thiſtles gather Figgs?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So that they have no cauſe to ſay, <hi>That we againſt them were,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>When as that we a <hi>threſhing</hi> went, we did not <hi>rave</hi> or <hi>tear.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For certainly, you may ſuppoſe, we did judge there was <hi>Corn</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Which prompted us to come and <hi>threſh,</hi> and <hi>winnow</hi> in your <hi>Barn.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And if the <hi>grain</hi> it did cling faſt, the <hi>chaffe</hi> and <hi>ſtraw</hi> unto,</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Threſhers</hi> do not <hi>diſcommend,</hi> tho they did it <hi>undo.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And though at firſt the <hi>beſt Corn</hi>'s made out of the <hi>Straw</hi> to ſpring</l>
                  <l>Yet do not you the <hi>Threſher</hi> blame, if it to th'reſt they <hi>fling.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For good <hi>full Corn</hi> it doth rejoyce, when <hi>Threſhers</hi> come thereto,</l>
                  <l>'Cauſe then it knows it ſhall be put Gods own will for to <hi>do.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And though it be but <hi>Oxen</hi> which this <hi>Corn</hi> out do <hi>tread,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yet by the ſame they <hi>food</hi> muſt have, and not be <hi>muzzelled.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>It is becauſe <hi>Corn</hi>'s hard and tough, that Inſtruments made be,</l>
                  <l>With <hi>ſharp hard Teeth,</hi> becauſe <hi>plain Tools</hi> from the <hi>Straw</hi> can't it <hi>free</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="33" facs="tcp:62159:17"/>
                  <l> So thoſe that good and godly were, we did them not contemn,</l>
                  <l>But what was done, was <hi>Gods viſit,</hi> did you to us commend.</l>
                  <l>For you were counted <hi>the loſt Sheep,</hi> of the <hi>Houſe Iſrael,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Therefore count us not Enemies becauſe <hi>Gods Truth</hi> we tell.</l>
                  <l>And by enquiry you did find, of <hi>Gods Meſſage</hi> worthy,</l>
                  <l>Though ſtill we ſee you hardned be, and us <hi>reproach daily.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>In the time of <hi>Elias</hi> though there <hi>Widows</hi> were a many,</l>
                  <l>He to <hi>Sareptha's Widow</hi>'s ſent, of others, not to any.</l>
                  <l>Alſo in <hi>Iſrael</hi> there was much <hi>Leproſie</hi> on man,</l>
                  <l>Yet none at all were cleanſed but <hi>Naaman</hi> the <hi>Syrian.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So that if God did ſend to cleanſe you of your <hi>Leproſie,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Then charge not the <hi>Meſſenger</hi> with <hi>Machivel-Policy.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Nor with the <hi>Prophet</hi> do find fault, that doth preſerve your ſtore,</l>
                  <l>When in great <hi>Famine</hi> that you were, he ſhew'd you <hi>where was more.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Moreover you may ſee thoſe men that zealous were indeed,</l>
                  <l>At the firſt <hi>threſhing</hi> did ſpring forth, and are reſerv'd for <hi>Seed.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The which the <hi>Promiſe</hi> is unto, and it <hi>inherit ſhall,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Becauſe in him they did <hi>believe,</hi> and anſwered his <hi>Call.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And they will teſtifie alſo, the <hi>Threſhers</hi> they did well,</l>
                  <l>Though they <hi>ſharp Inſtruments</hi> did uſe, 'twas good to them befel.</l>
                  <l>For ſeeing they were <hi>hungry Souls,</hi> Heavens <hi>Bread,</hi> tho it be <hi>bitter,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Now they were juſt a coming forth of <hi>Egypt,</hi> was the fitter.</l>
                  <l>And as for being <hi>Flatterers,</hi> or that at <hi>Court</hi> have <hi>favour,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Our <hi>Sufferings they</hi> will teſtify, in <hi>Court</hi> we have no <hi>ſavour,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Nor ought on <hi>Earth</hi> to <hi>appeal to,</hi> but that we <hi>lye down ſtill,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And <hi>ſuffer all</hi> for <hi>Chriſt his ſake,</hi> for this we know's <hi>Gods will.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Alſo in this we do rejoyce, that we <hi>with him partake,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Both in his <hi>Sufferings</hi> and his <hi>Death,</hi> this <hi>Baptim</hi>'s for his ſake.</l>
                  <l>And as for your <hi>Idol flattring,</hi> with us there's no ſuch thing,</l>
                  <l>As <hi>Cap,</hi> or <hi>Knee,</hi> or <hi>Worſhip,</hi> which makes <hi>Courts</hi> againſt us <hi>ring.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And cauſe we can't it to them give, no favour they do ſhow,</l>
                  <l>Yea unto <hi>us</hi> they do not <hi>right,</hi> as moſt of you do know.</l>
                  <l>And as for our <hi>not going now,</hi> oh that would you <hi>diſgrace,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Should we cry out on <hi>Anti-chriſt,</hi> who you ſay's in your <hi>Place.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>No, no, if that <hi>Anti-christ</hi> doth this your Church now <hi>poſſeſs,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Againſt him then you ſhould <hi>declare,</hi> tis your part now, we gueſs.</l>
                  <l>And that he might not never more ariſe, much leſs to ſtand,</l>
                  <l>You made the People <hi>Covenant,</hi> againſt him through the Land,</l>
                  <l>With <hi>Hands</hi> lift up to <hi>Heaven high,</hi> that God he would <hi>record,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This <hi>Solemn League</hi> and <hi>Covenant,</hi> you have made to <hi>the Lord.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="34" facs="tcp:62159:18"/>
                  <l> And yet are picking upon us to do your <hi>drugery,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Muſt we fulfill your <hi>Covenant,</hi> and for't in <hi>Priſon lye?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Then may you ſay we're <hi>Fools</hi> indeed, and <hi>Buſie-bodies too,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>To meddle in <hi>others matters</hi> where, ſo little thanks is due.</l>
                  <l>But if that you have <hi>vowd</hi> a <hi>Vow,</hi> defer it not to <hi>pay,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For God in <hi>Fools</hi> no <hi>pleaſure</hi> takes, tis true what I do ſay.</l>
                  <l>But from us this <hi>Proviſo</hi> take, <hi>With no Weapons contend,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But <hi>Heart</hi> and <hi>Tongue,</hi> with Gods own <hi>Breath,</hi> and <hi>Spirit</hi> he doth ſend.</l>
                  <l>For <hi>Creature-killing-Weapons</hi> they, are <hi>Antichriſts</hi> own <hi>Arms,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And you will never <hi>overcome</hi> by any ſuch like <hi>Charms.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>But now with us Gods <hi>Standard's</hi> ſet, and <hi>Goſhans</hi> Land is known</l>
                  <l>Where <hi>Light</hi> to <hi>Iſrael</hi> doth <hi>ſhine,</hi> as I before have ſhown.</l>
                  <l>Sor if <hi>inward Egyptians</hi> will, true <hi>Iſ-ra-el-ites</hi> turn,</l>
                  <l>This <hi>Houſe</hi> of <hi>God</hi> ſtill open ſtands for them to come and <hi>Learn.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>More than all <hi>Egypts Sorcerers,</hi> or her <hi>Magicians,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Can teach, becauſe tis very clear, <hi>Gods Power tranſcendeth Mans.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Now the Lord hath deliverance ſent to his <hi>Daughter SION,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That dwelleth with the <hi>Daughter</hi> of <hi>MYSTERY Babylon.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For among <hi>natural bruit Beaſts</hi> there is no <hi>Myſtery,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>With <hi>outward Sheep</hi> and <hi>inward Wolves,</hi> the <hi>Myſtery</hi> here doth ly.</l>
                  <l>For <hi>Foxes, Lyons, Wolves</hi> and <hi>Bears,</hi> there ſhape doth them diſcover,</l>
                  <l>What ſpirit tis doth lodge in them, ſo doth their <hi>Voyce,</hi> moreover</l>
                  <l>Shew forth and alſo warning give to Man and Beaſt, <hi>beware</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Leſt on them they do make their <hi>prey,</hi> being caught in their <hi>Snare.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Theſe Beaſts in their <hi>earthly Nature,</hi> act right within their <hi>Sphere,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Though <hi>tyrannizing</hi> or'e the reſt, keeping them all in <hi>fear.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But when theſe alter <hi>Voice</hi> and <hi>Shape,</hi> what <hi>ſphere</hi> run in they then,</l>
                  <l>Having <hi>Sheeps-cloathing</hi> with <hi>Lambs voice,</hi> they then <hi>devour Men.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>'Twas the ſtrict Sect of <hi>Phariſees</hi> and <hi>Writing Scribes</hi> alſo,</l>
                  <l>That Jeſus Chriſt call'd <hi>Hypocrites,</hi> 'gainſt them denounſt his <hi>wo.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Calling them <hi>Fools, Serpents, Blind-guides,</hi> and <hi>Vipers Children</hi> to,</l>
                  <l>And alſo <hi>Painted Sepulchers,</hi> ſuch names he counts their due.</l>
                  <l>The reaſon of't if you would know, <hi>Matthew</hi> doth it repeat,</l>
                  <l>Their <hi>Burdens, Scourgings, Devourings,</hi> tho they got <hi>Moſes Seat,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Their <hi>C<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>ing</hi> and <hi>Pretences</hi> too, <hi>Long Prayers</hi> they did make,</l>
                  <l>And <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <hi>Tombes</hi> and <hi>Sepulchers,</hi> theſe courſes they did take.</l>
                  <l>
                     <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap> Sons and Fathers <hi>Prophets</hi> kill'd, <hi>Wiſe Men</hi> and <hi>Chriſt alſo,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap> ſcourged in their Synagogues,</hi> and much <hi>Blood ſpite</hi> from mo.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="35" facs="tcp:62159:18"/>
               <head>Something as to the ORDER in our Meetings, wherein we do not Reſpect Perſons, for which the Spirit ſtirs up to Perſecution.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>THeſe <hi>Meetings</hi> and <hi>Aſſemblies</hi> are ſuch as <hi>James</hi> doth us tell,</l>
                  <l>Where <hi>Gay-cloathing</hi> had no reſpect, nor did <hi>Gold-rings</hi> excel.</l>
                  <l>For in our <hi>Meeting-Place</hi> there's no chief ſeats kept, but thoſe</l>
                  <l>That do the <hi>vileſt rayment wear,</hi> may ſit as doth <hi>gay cloathes.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For we dare not commit this ſin, <hi>Mens perſons to respect,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Leſt while before him we appear, <hi>our Service he reject.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Advantages we do not ſeek, that we may men <hi>admire,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Nor can we <hi>fawn</hi> on them for ought, or bid them <hi>ſit up higher;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For we be thoſe that do believe, no honour do <hi>receive,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Nor dare we ought to others <hi>give,</hi> God never gave us <hi>leave.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But honour do we in the Lord, all men it is their due,</l>
                  <l>But when men ſeek it to themſelves, we give it not thereto.</l>
                  <l>For no man hath <hi>that which is good,</hi> or ought thats <hi>honourable,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>It is no more than <hi>Crumbs</hi> that <hi>fall</hi> from <hi>Gods Almighty Table.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Why ſhould the <hi>Riv'let</hi> boaſt it ſelf, which by the <hi>Fountain's</hi> fed,</l>
                  <l>And what hath Man <hi>to glory in,</hi> who <hi>beggs his daily Bread?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For 'tis of <hi>Grace</hi> all that we have, his <hi>Gifts</hi> we live upon,</l>
                  <l>Therefore to him let's <hi>Praiſes</hi> give, yea unto him alone.</l>
                  <l>Moreover ſhould we <hi>honour give,</hi> to men, which they count <hi>civil,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>We know'ts a <hi>ſnare,</hi> and we muſt <hi>ſhun, appearances of evil.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Did not this vanity help much, to haſten <hi>Herods</hi> doom,</l>
                  <l>When th' People cryed <hi>The voice of God, and not of man, is come?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This honour to himſelf he took, 'twas a <hi>temptation,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſought the <hi>glory to himſelf,</hi> the which was <hi>Gods alone.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So with an <hi>Angel</hi> he was <hi>ſmote,</hi> God <hi>vengeance</hi> on him took,</l>
                  <l>And with <hi>Worms</hi> then <hi>he eaten was,</hi> on this to us is ſpoke.</l>
                  <l>For he a <hi>Perſecutor</hi> was, this only doth afford,</l>
                  <l>With hands ſtretcht out to <hi>vex the Church,</hi> he killd <hi>James</hi> with the <hi>Sword,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And becauſe he did ſee it pleas'd the <hi>Jews;</hi> he did proceed</l>
                  <l>And apprehended <hi>Peter</hi> too, all <hi>Truth</hi> thus out <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 word">
                        <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                     </gap> weed,</l>
                  <pb n="36" facs="tcp:62159:19"/>
                  <l> But when to God <hi>Prayer</hi> was made for <hi>Peter, God did hear,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And by his <hi>Angel</hi> did him from <hi>Blood-ſucking Herod</hi> clear.</l>
                  <l>And for his <hi>Pride</hi> and <hi>Cruelty</hi> in recompence God paid,</l>
                  <l>And brought his <hi>Judgements</hi> upon him, as I before have ſaid.</l>
                  <l>Theſe are the <hi>Hamonites</hi> of old, which in themſelves do ſay,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Who ſhall the King, or the People honour, but us alway,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But ſee what he unto himſelf, as <hi>honour</hi> thus did crave,</l>
                  <l>Was given unto <hi>Mordecay,</hi> whom he ordain'd his <hi>Slave.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>Gallows-meaſure</hi> he had made, for to <hi>hang Mordecay,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Was meaſured unto himſelf, for thus the King did ſay;</l>
                  <l>For <hi>when the King once knew the thing,</hi> h'ſaid, <hi>Hang him thereupon,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thus on <hi>proud wicked mens Heads</hi> fall, <hi>Gods Judgements</hi> many a one</l>
                  <l>This was the man that thought it ſcorn, <hi>Ones blood</hi> to ſeek alone,</l>
                  <l>But all his <hi>Brethren</hi> the <hi>Jews,</hi> muſt be kill'd every one.</l>
                  <l>And though but one commit th' <hi>Offence,</hi> not to his <hi>Pride to bow,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yet all the reſt muſt <hi>ſuffer</hi> for't, ſo it is <hi>decreed now.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So <hi>Hamon</hi> is the firſt of all, that ever yet I've read,</l>
                  <l>Who got forth ſuch a <hi>cruel Law,</hi> yet we find of his <hi>Seed.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Thus alſo <hi>Nebuchadnezzar,</hi> who in his <hi>Pallace</hi> walkt,</l>
                  <l>Said, <hi>Is not this Great</hi> Babylon (with much ſuch glorying talkt)</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>That I have built, for the Houſe of the Kingdom, that is mine,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And by the might of my Power,</hi> (thus ſlighting Gods <hi>Divine</hi>)</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And alſo for the honour of alone my Majeſty,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>As if at all there had not been, a <hi>Power</hi> that's on high.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>While theſe words were in the Kings mouth, there fell a voice from heaven,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>The Kingdom is departed now, that unto thee was given.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This was the <hi>Image-making man,</hi> and <hi>Perſecutor too,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That caſt i'th <hi>fire</hi> who would not to's <hi>Image</hi> Worſhip do.</l>
                  <l>Therefore let none think that we do't through <hi>peeviſhneſs of mind,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For we for it good <hi>Reaſon</hi> have, and <hi>Precepts too Divine,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Examples</hi> too, you ſee we have, recorded in <hi>Scripture.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Of <hi>Gods Judgements,</hi> that on men fell, which were both juſt and ſure,</l>
                  <l>As hard-hearted <hi>Pharaoh</hi> did keep <hi>Iſrael</hi> in Bondage great,</l>
                  <l>And when <hi>Liberty</hi> it was ſought, with God he would not treat:</l>
                  <l>But ſaid, <hi>Who is the Lord, that he, at all ſhould him obey?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>With ſuch preſumptuous words as theſe from his <hi>proud heart</hi> did ſay,</l>
                  <l>And in the ſtead of <hi>Liberty,</hi> did make their <hi>Burthens</hi> more,</l>
                  <l>For which upon his Head God did, full many <hi>Judgements</hi> poure.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Bloody waters, Froggs, Lice</hi> and <hi>Flies,</hi> with <hi>Boyles</hi> and <hi>Blanches</hi> many,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Hail, Locuſts, Darkneſs,</hi> and <hi>Firſt-born,</hi> were ſlain, he left not any.</l>
                  <pb n="37" facs="tcp:62159:19"/>
                  <l> And yet for all thoſe <hi>Judgements</hi> which fell on him as his due,</l>
                  <l>So <hi>hard-hearted</hi> he yet ſtill was, that <hi>Iſrael</hi> he'd <hi>purſue.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So Gods People in a great ſtrait, being thus <hi>ſurrounded,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>By ſtanding kill <hi>Salvation</hi> ſaw, of God, and <hi>Pharaoh drounded,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This is for you a <hi>warning</hi> then, that follow ſtep by ſtep,</l>
                  <l>That regard not <hi>Fire, War,</hi> or <hi>Plague,</hi> but over theſe things lep,</l>
                  <l>Tho you count thoſe things <hi>Accidents,</hi> which unto you are given,</l>
                  <l>But that you ſhould no <hi>Covers</hi> have, <hi>God ſhews you ſigns from heaven:</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yea, and <hi>ſuch ſigns</hi> all your <hi>Wiſe men,</hi> with their <hi>Egyptian Art,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Could tell the coming of the ſame, which made them all to ſtart.</l>
                  <l>Nor what th' effect or influence theſe <hi>Blaſing-Stars</hi> would be,</l>
                  <l>That in one year did ſhew themſelves not one, or two, but three.</l>
                  <l>Thus <hi>Pharaohs</hi> drown'd, and <hi>Hamons</hi> hang'd, <hi>Nebuchadnezzar's</hi> due.</l>
                  <l>To loſe his <hi>Kingdom,</hi> and <hi>Herod,</hi> eaten with worms was to,</l>
                  <l>So all <hi>proud perſecuting Spirits, Examples</hi> here's for you,</l>
                  <l>For God is now the ſame, alſo, his <hi>Judgements juſt</hi> and <hi>true.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For his Hand is not ſhortned, but can help, 'tis our ſtay,</l>
                  <l>Nor is his power now weakend, more than 'twas yeſterday.</l>
                  <l>For all the <hi>Honour</hi> and <hi>Glory,</hi> of Man is but a lye,</l>
                  <l>And if there were no <hi>Worſhippers</hi> of <hi>Idols</hi> they would dye.</l>
                  <l>This <hi>Honour</hi> God he will not give to graven <hi>Images,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Nor his <hi>Glory</hi> to mortal men, tho they him near ſo pleaſe,</l>
                  <l>For that the <hi>Kingdom</hi> it is his, the <hi>Power</hi> and <hi>Glory</hi> too,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Honour</hi> for ever and e're, to him alone tis due.</l>
                  <l>For if the <hi>Angel</hi> which to <hi>John,</hi> ſhewd <hi>Myſteries</hi> manifold,</l>
                  <l>Would not be <hi>bow'd</hi> to or <hi>worſhipt,</hi> how dare man be ſo bold?</l>
                  <l>For he our <hi>Fellow-ſervant</hi> was, and of our <hi>Brethren</hi> to,</l>
                  <l>Which <hi>Jeſus Teſtimony had,</hi> and <hi>Propheſying Spirit</hi> true.</l>
                  <l>Theſe are the higheſt <hi>attainments</hi> of <hi>Angels</hi> and of <hi>Men,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That maketh them <hi>honourable,</hi> yet are they but <hi>Brethren.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſo they dare not now to <hi>bow,</hi> or <hi>worſhip</hi> give each other,</l>
                  <l>Or <hi>glory</hi> in ought that they have, for't cometh from another.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>And now all earthly <hi>Images,</hi> you all muſt now be dumbe,</l>
                  <l>And ſpeak no more for your glory, now <hi>Gods Kingdom is come.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And his <hi>Almighty Power</hi> ſhall you altogether grind,</l>
                  <l>And in the <hi>Sea</hi> your <hi>Aſhes</hi> caſt, that henceforth none you find.</l>
                  <l>This is the <hi>little Stone</hi> the which out of the <hi>Mountain's</hi> cut,</l>
                  <l>Though without hands, your <hi>Images</hi> ſhall break, as a ſmall <hi>Nut.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Theſe <hi>Idols</hi> of <hi>Silver</hi> and <hi>Gold,</hi> they ſhall to <hi>Moles</hi> be given,</l>
                  <l>The which <hi>blind Vermin</hi> in Earth creep, ſhut up from th' <hi>Light of heaven.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="38" facs="tcp:62159:20"/>
                  <l> And the blind <hi>Bats</hi> muſt have a part, that are <hi>Birds of the night,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The which cannot abide the <hi>Day,</hi> to fly in peoples <hi>ſight.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Therefore alone to God we'l <hi>bow,</hi> and <hi>worſhip</hi> him alway,</l>
                  <l>Who is our <hi>Fountain, Treaſure, Stock,</hi> our <hi>Light, Life, Bread</hi> and <hi>Stay,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And therefore now, Man <hi>ſpeak no more</hi> for <hi>to be bow'd unto,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For <hi>Gods Prerogative it is,</hi> and he muſt have his due.</l>
                  <l>If <hi>Saints</hi> and <hi>Angels</hi> they would not at all be <hi>bow'd</hi> to, then</l>
                  <l>What ſpirit have all thoſe that do, <hi>ſeek worſhip now from men?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For if Gods <hi>Meſſengers</hi> and <hi>Gifts</hi> we muſt not once <hi>admire,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Oh then! Whoſe <hi>Meſſengers</hi> are they, that <hi>Glory</hi> do deſire?</l>
                  <l>For all the <hi>Gifts</hi> and <hi>Graces</hi> w<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>ch God he doth to us ſend,</l>
                  <l>That him alone we ſhould <hi>praiſe,</hi> which, is both <hi>Author</hi> and <hi>End.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For we the <hi>Iſrael</hi> of God are, while we walk in <hi>this ſphere,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So no <hi>Weapon</hi> againſt us formd ſhall <hi>prosper, Sword</hi> or <hi>Spear.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>If in the <hi>Fire</hi> we are caſt, oh there's the <hi>Son of God,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Or through the <hi>Water</hi> made to paſs, oh there's alſo the <hi>Lord.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So to be <hi>burnt</hi> or <hi>over-flowd,</hi> no cauſe we have to fear,</l>
                  <l>For <hi>Angels Lyons mouths do ſtop,</hi> of's <hi>Daniels</hi> he hath care.</l>
                  <l>If <hi>Oxen</hi> muſt not <hi>muzzeld</hi> be, that do tread out the <hi>Corn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Oh then what <hi>care</hi> will he have of his <hi>Babes</hi> that are <hi>new born?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But if that yet we do <hi>pleaſe men,</hi> Gods <hi>Servants</hi> we are not,</l>
                  <l>And when men worldly honour ſeek, it ſignifies a <hi>Blot.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That they from God departed are in whom men <hi>honour have,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And gone into the <hi>World</hi> from him, who do its <hi>honour crave.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Saul</hi> is a <hi>figure</hi> unto ſuch, who <hi>Gods Word</hi> diſobeyd,</l>
                  <l>And God from him departed was, oh then he cryd, and ſaid</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Before the People honour me,</hi> oh this was all his cry,</l>
                  <l>For thoſe that have <hi>forſaken God,</hi> on this alone rely.</l>
                  <l>But this is ſad and deſmal to, <hi>Worlds</hi> glory for to gain,</l>
                  <l>Out of Gods preſence to be caſt into <hi>eternal pain.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>In this <hi>Doctrine</hi> it is obſerv'd, the <hi>Perſecutors proud,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Which will not to this <hi>Image bow, Life</hi> hardly is allow'd.</l>
                  <l>And God he is ſo juſt and true, in <hi>Judgement</hi> he'll not act,</l>
                  <l>Till plainly the <hi>notoriouſneſs appear doth of the Fact.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Cain</hi> he cannot at all be caſt out of <hi>Gods preſence</hi> till,</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Blood of</hi> Abel <hi>he hath ſpilt,</hi> then <hi>Judgement on him fell.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So you that <hi>offer unto God, the Sacrifice of Praiſe,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Which <hi>Offering</hi> he doth reſpect, and alſo did alwayes.</l>
                  <l>Thus to the <hi>Will of God</hi> you muſt your ſelves and all commit,</l>
                  <l>Tho <hi>Caldees</hi> and <hi>Sabeans</hi> too, themſelves againſt you ſet.</l>
                  <pb n="39" facs="tcp:62159:20"/>
                  <l> For the Chaſtiſements of the Lord, we never muſt refuſe,</l>
                  <l>'Cauſe ye no <hi>Baſtards</hi> are but <hi>Sons,</hi> he to himſelf doth chuſe.</l>
                  <l>And when that you <hi>corrected</hi> are, <hi>Obedience</hi> thereby learn,</l>
                  <l>You ſhall not need to fear but God, the <hi>Rod</hi> forthwith will burn.</l>
                  <l>Now if the ground-work you would know, in fine, of all this evil,</l>
                  <l>From th' <hi>Dragon</hi> and <hi>old Serpent</hi> tis, or ſpirit of the <hi>Devil.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The which, beſides Old <hi>Adam,</hi> did ſet on to tempt the Lord,</l>
                  <l>And in's <hi>temptations</hi> offered, what the <hi>World could afford.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>Kingdom, power,</hi> and <hi>glory,</hi> to him he would allow,</l>
                  <l>And ſaid twas his, to give to thoſe, that unto him would <hi>bow.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Though he himſelf a wandrer were up and down in the Earth,</l>
                  <l>Our <hi>adverſary</hi> doth appear, to devour <hi>Spiritual birth.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This Spirit you ſhall ſee in them that do worlds glory ſeek,</l>
                  <l>And ſuch as <hi>flatter, fawn</hi> and <hi>bow,</hi> to them they'll appear <hi>meek,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But any one that fears the Lord, and cant to <hi>proud fleſh bow,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>No <hi>favour, love,</hi> or <hi>curteſie,</hi> to ſuch he doth allow.</l>
                  <l>Though his neceſſities be great, as Chriſts were alſo, when,</l>
                  <l>He <hi>faſted forty nights and dayes,</hi> a hungry he was then.</l>
                  <l>And this the <hi>Devil</hi> he did know, to him it did appear,</l>
                  <l>Becauſe Chriſt would not bow to him, he therefore did him jear,</l>
                  <l>To ſatisfie his own hunger, <hi>Bids him with ſtones make bread.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>His own neceſſities to help if he meant to be fed.</l>
                  <l>And further miſchiefs he contriv'd, and dangers what he could,</l>
                  <l>When put upon <hi>the Pinacle</hi> himſelf <hi>caſt from he ſhould;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For if thou be Gods Son,</hi> he ſaid, <hi>the Angels they have Charge,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And in their hands they ſhould bear up and keep thy feet at large;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Leſt thou at any time ſhouldſt daſh thy foot againſt a ſtone,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Theſe were the <hi>ſnares, affronts</hi> and <hi>jears,</hi> our Lord he put upon.</l>
                  <l>But in <hi>Gods Power</hi> he did them bear, of him we are to <hi>learn,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And to <hi>ſuffer</hi> all for his ſake, tho brought we are to <hi>burn.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Object.</head>
                  <l>But ſome may ſay, <hi>That thou doſt treat, 'gainſt Gods Commandement,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which bids us honour our Parents, this is the true Intent.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Anſw.</head>
                  <l>For <hi>Anſwer</hi> hereunto, I ſay, This honour do we give,</l>
                  <l>There wants and their neceſſities, we always do relieve.</l>
                  <pb n="40" facs="tcp:62159:21"/>
                  <l> This is the true <hi>Honour</hi> the which Chriſt he himſelf did ſay,</l>
                  <l>Though <hi>Jews Traditions</hi> made it void, and <hi>Gods Law</hi> diſobey.</l>
                  <l>For what <hi>profit</hi> our <hi>Parents</hi> do receive from us at all,</l>
                  <l>Is but returning of their own, <hi>Corban,</hi> we don't it call.</l>
                  <l>If in the Lord our <hi>Parents</hi> be, we <hi>honour them</hi> alſo,</l>
                  <l>And if the Lord do <hi>honour</hi> them, How can we then ſay no?</l>
                  <l>This is as 'tis in <hi>Marriages,</hi> are only in the <hi>Lord,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Where only is the <hi>
                        <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>nity,</hi> and the alone <hi>Accord.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For here's no <hi>caring for the World,</hi> the <hi>Husband</hi> for to pleaſe,</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Husband</hi> being <hi>in the Lord,</hi> they both are ſerv'd with eaſe.</l>
                  <l>When <hi>Wife</hi> and <hi>Husband</hi> both do ſeek, the <hi>Lord for to obey,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>What can the <hi>Wife</hi> or <hi>Husband do,</hi> that either will <hi>gain-ſay?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For <hi>pleaſe the Lord,</hi> the <hi>Wife</hi> is pleas'd, if <hi>in the Lord ſhe be,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And <hi>pleaſe the Lord,</hi> the <hi>Husband</hi>'s pleaſ'd, <hi>if in the Lord be he.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And if at all a jar ariſe, they ſhall each other heal,</l>
                  <l>Till the thing plain be ſignifi'd, and God doth it reveal.</l>
                  <l>Yea this will be to <hi>Parents</hi> to, when <hi>in the Lord</hi> they be,</l>
                  <l>We <hi>honour</hi> do and <hi>pleaſe</hi> them both, when that they do agree.</l>
                  <l>This is the <hi>double honour too</hi> the <hi>Elder is to have,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>That in the World and Doctrine both do labour ſouls to ſave.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And this is not before People, that we do them <hi>admire,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>They being <hi>in the Lord,</hi> do not at all ſuch things <hi>deſire.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="poem">
               <pb n="41" facs="tcp:62159:21"/>
               <head>The Grand SCRUPLE and OBJECTION ANSWERED.</head>
               <lg>
                  <head>Object.</head>
                  <l>BUT ſome may ſay, <hi>You fickle are, and know not where to fix,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And you in many</hi> Forms <hi>have been, in</hi> ſeven, <hi>or at leaſt</hi> ſix.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>When you from us at first did go,</hi> Puritans <hi>you would be,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>But when the</hi> Scotiſh-Broiles <hi>began, you cryd,</hi> Presbyter<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 letter">
                        <desc>•</desc>
                     </gap>e.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And ſo in</hi> War <hi>you would fight for't, in it ſome</hi> Blood <hi>you ſpent,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Yet here you could not fix at all, but turn</hi> Independent.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And ſo you ſeveral Churches were, with Power ſeverally,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And then you broke up Churches to, and did them all deny.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Becauſe you ſaid,</hi> They were not built on the Foundation,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And all the Ordinances loſt, for</hi> Pope <hi>was</hi> Corner-ſtone.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Oh then did you bethink your ſelves, what then was beſt to do,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>To Bail theſe Churches, and to get more Ordinances New.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For that this</hi> Anti-chriſtian Pope, <hi>the former he had ſpoild,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And now they muſt have all anew, the others being defild.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And then a great</hi> Contention <hi>roſe, who ſhould this ſame begin,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And who ſhould</hi> John <hi>the</hi> Baptiſt <hi>be, ſith none were free from ſin.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And all had need to be waſhed, becauſe that there was none</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>The which had</hi> Gods Word <hi>come to him, as it did come to</hi> John.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Neither that Power nor Spirit which could bring ſuch things to paſs,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>By turning hearts to God as did the Prophet</hi> E-li-as.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>At laſt this work it was begun, there's very few know how,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And many this Tradition took, to it did many flow,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And ſo in many Bodies grew, yet here were not content,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which ſhews that you are wavering, being</hi> Incontinent.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For here you did not tarry long, but anon preſently,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>So great was your</hi> Ambition <hi>grown, muſt be a</hi> Monarchy</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And that not only a ſmall one, (you count your ſelves to thrive)</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>The World contains but four great ones, and you must make them five.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>So when that this great power came forth, your building that was <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>igh,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>You ſaid your ſelves,</hi> 'twas but rotten, and Foundation ſandy,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For that as ſoon as any ſtorm, on this your houſe did blow,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Your</hi> Monarchy <hi>came tumbling down; into the duſt full-<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>ow.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="42" facs="tcp:62159:22"/>
                  <l> 
                     <hi>And then when in the duſt you were, not knowing what to do,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>When all your heavenly Building fell, you went a ſeeking to.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And by that name you did confeſs, ſtill that there is a want,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Your Souls not being ſatisfied, for that they ſtill do pant.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>So what ſhall we that do ſtand by, of ye now for to make,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Who Valliant Famous Builders were, but now are made to Quake;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And now for it are Quakers called, your Laborinth is ſuch;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>So many means, and ways you've tryed we dare not with you tuch.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Anſw.</head>
                  <l>For <hi>Anſwer</hi> hereunto I ſay, theſe things do not diſpiſe,</l>
                  <l>For when the Lord did <hi>Samuel</hi> call, he preſently did riſe,</l>
                  <l>And ran forthwith to Old <hi>Ely,</hi> and ſaid, <hi>lo here am I,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For that thou now dideſt call me,</hi> and I came by and by:</l>
                  <l>Then <hi>Ely</hi> bid him <hi>go to reſt, and ly him down again,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But the Lord called <hi>Samuel</hi> before he long had layn;</l>
                  <l>Then <hi>Samuel</hi> roſe the ſecond time, and to <hi>Ely</hi> did ſay,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Here I am for thou did'ſt call me;</hi> he Anſwered, <hi>nay, nay,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But the Lord ſtill calls <hi>Samuel</hi> again the third time to,</l>
                  <l>Who forth with went to <hi>Ely</hi> then, to know what he ſhould do;</l>
                  <l>And that with this great confidence and ſaid <hi>he did him call,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That t'was the Lord <hi>Ely perceived</hi> that called theſe times all:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Samuel</hi> did not yet know the Lord, nor ought by him was ſed;</l>
                  <l>Gods Word to him was not ſhowen, nor yet was re-ve-led.</l>
                  <l>But <hi>Samuel, Samuel</hi> cal'd is ſtill, and a fourth time alſo;</l>
                  <l>Before he knows it is the Lord, then <hi>here's thy Servant lo.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Then do not you condemn us when 'twas God who ſtill did call,</l>
                  <l>Though we run to the Outward Prieſt and Ordinances all,</l>
                  <l>And ſecond, third, and forth way, God calling of us ſtill,</l>
                  <l>We could not reſt, but we muſt riſe till we did know his will.</l>
                  <l>If for our zeal you us condemn, <hi>Samuel</hi> muſt ſtand our Friend,</l>
                  <l>To ſpeak for us when that God will to <hi>Jeſſes</hi> houſe him ſend.</l>
                  <l>Who there, for us, will make excuſe, for this our <hi>Ignorance,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>When he did judge <hi>God annointed</hi> with his outward eyes glance.</l>
                  <l>For the Lord ſaid, <hi>he ſhould not look on outward countenance,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Nor on the height of the ſtature, though it was</hi> Jeſſes <hi>Branch,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For by that way, God doth not look, neither by it doth chuſe,</l>
                  <l>For what accords not with his heart, that ſtill he doth refuſe.</l>
                  <l>Here <hi>Samuel</hi> took the <hi>firſt-born Son,</hi> for <hi>Gods Annointed</hi> ſure,</l>
                  <l>But <hi>Countenance</hi> nor <hi>Stature</hi> doth anſwer to God the pure.</l>
                  <pb n="43" facs="tcp:62159:22"/>
                  <l> So ſecond, third, and all ſeven, paſt before <hi>Samuel,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But no anſwer from God he had of them as he could tell.</l>
                  <l>So being at a ſtand he ſaid, <hi>are here all thy Children?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>David</hi> unworthy counted was to be with his <hi>Brethren;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yet by the Lord <hi>annointed</hi> is, whatere of him is ſed,</l>
                  <l>For Gods Spirit on him is pourd, <hi>Sure mercies of David.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thus you ſee all the ſeven Sons, diſowned by their <hi>Maker,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But this ſame laſt <hi>Sheep-keeping lad,</hi> becauſe he was a <hi>Quaker.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>All here may ſee that God doth chuſe the heart that is upright,</l>
                  <l>Which tremble doth at his own Word, is pleaſant in his ſight.</l>
                  <l>So we can ſay in truth of heart, when God did firſt us call,</l>
                  <l>And we ran in the ſeveral wayes (yea, ſome have run them all)</l>
                  <l>In ſomething we did anſwer him, that pleaſd him, we do know,</l>
                  <l>That he never left calling us, till his <hi>Truth us did ſhow.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So the <hi>Laſt way</hi> ſome did profeſs was no Form but <hi>Seeking,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>By <hi>Babylons fall</hi> they all did ceaſe, but now is found the thing.</l>
                  <l>The <hi>MESSIAH</hi> that doth <hi>reſtore Iſrael</hi> that was loſt</l>
                  <l>The which hath ſuffered much <hi>Shipwrack</hi> is caſt upon our coaſt.</l>
                  <l>So the <hi>ſure Mercies</hi> we have found, the <hi>Christ,</hi> the <hi>first,</hi> the <hi>last,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>Spirit of the Living God,</hi> which was in Ages paſt.</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Chriſt</hi> by the fleſh was <hi>Davids Son,</hi> he being his <hi>Off-ſpring,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But yet in Spirit was <hi>Davids Root,</hi> for <hi>David</hi> calls him <hi>King.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Here anſwerd is the great <hi>Queſtion</hi> that doth with <hi>Truth</hi> accord,</l>
                  <l>How <hi>Jeſus Chriſt</hi> not only was <hi>Davids</hi> own <hi>Son,</hi> but <hi>Lord?</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This is the <hi>King that, God hath ſet upon his holy Hill,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>That ſhall the <hi>Pot-ſhards</hi> of <hi>Earth break,</hi> that bow not to his <hi>Will.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>God being a <hi>Spirit,</hi> his <hi>Son</hi> is <hi>ſo,</hi> and ſo of right is <hi>Lord.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Who <hi>was,</hi> and <hi>is,</hi> and <hi>ever ſhall</hi> be <hi>King,</hi> with one accord,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>His Day</hi> Chriſt ſaid, <hi>Abram did ſee,</hi> tho ſome him for't did ſcorn,</l>
                  <l>The <hi>Everlaſting Father</hi> was, though <hi>Iſays Child new-born,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This was the <hi>Scepter which was not from Iſrael to depart,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The <hi>inward Iſrael indeed,</hi> who're <hi>Circumciſ'd in heart.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This <hi>Law giver 'tween Judas feet,</hi> yea nearer, <hi>in his womb,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Who never ſhall from his <hi>depart, until that SHILO come.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>This was the <hi>Spiritual meat</hi> and <hi>drink,</hi> this was the <hi>ſtore</hi> the <hi>ſtock,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Of <hi>Iſrael, that followed them to drink,</hi> tis <hi>Chriſt the Rock,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Yea this <hi>the Rock of Ages is, it was,</hi> and <hi>ſhall be</hi> ſo,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Generations Foundation,</hi> no other ſhall they know,</l>
                  <l>So now that former <hi>fickle State,</hi> in which we wore wavering</l>
                  <l>Being wholly unſatisfied, until we had our <hi>King.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="44" facs="tcp:62159:23"/>
                  <l> But now our <hi>Lord</hi> and <hi>King</hi> is come, and in our hearts doth <hi>raign,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And hath our <hi>Enemies, Sin</hi> and <hi>Death,</hi> in <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 span">
                        <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                     </gap>eat meaſure <hi>ſlain,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So I again to you do ſay, do not upbraid us more,</l>
                  <l>With ſuch a <hi>fickle wavering ſtate,</hi> as you have done before.</l>
                  <l>When in <hi>dead Forms,</hi> and <hi>outward Prieſts,</hi> which periſh with uſing,</l>
                  <l>We neither <hi>handle, touch</hi> or <hi>taſte</hi> with you any ſuch thing.</l>
                  <l>Wherefore your <hi>outward viſible Signs,</hi> muſt all of them give place,</l>
                  <l>According to your <hi>Liturgy,</hi> 'tis <hi>inward ſpiritual Grace,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The which <hi>now</hi> in the <hi>heart</hi> doth <hi>raign,</hi> of <hi>many</hi> in this <hi>Nation,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For <hi>outward Shaddows</hi> were but till the time of <hi>Reformation.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But now the good things they are come, <hi>Chriſt Body</hi> is diſcern'd,</l>
                  <l>And <hi>Gods Kingdom</hi> of <hi>Righteouſneſs,</hi> of <hi>Joy</hi> and <hi>Peace</hi> is learn'd.</l>
                  <l>The which in <hi>Meats</hi> and <hi>Drinks</hi> doth not conſiſt as many think,</l>
                  <l>For in this <hi>Kingdom</hi> we afreſh with <hi>Chriſt</hi> this fruit do drink.</l>
                  <l>And therefore all your <hi>Waſhings</hi> then, that divers were and many.</l>
                  <l>With all your worldly <hi>Elements</hi> that doth not perfect any:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For the Body Chriſt hath prepard, to do thy will, O God,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For that thy People willing be in this days Power, O Lord.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And now may'nt I ſay, <hi>Glory to</hi> (as well as <hi>Englands Form</hi>)</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>The Father, Son, and holy Ghoſt,</hi> in it I ſee no harm.</l>
                  <l>And that <hi>in the beginning 'twas</hi> (I alſo ſay the ſame)</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>So it ſhall be world without end,</hi> Praiſe <hi>to his Holy NAME.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>His <hi>Name</hi>'s but one, and yet to him there many <hi>Names</hi> are given,</l>
                  <l>According as he Miniſters to us here under <hi>Heaven,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And here on <hi>Earth Three</hi> record bear (tho <hi>Three</hi>) in <hi>ONE</hi> agree,</l>
                  <l>And anſwer <hi>Heavens record</hi> to, as <hi>Branches</hi> of <hi>ONE Tree.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Some more SCRUPLES clear'd.</head>
                  <l>NOW for the opening of the <hi>Truth,</hi> which is our <hi>ſtrength</hi> &amp;c <hi>ſtay.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>In <hi>anſwering</hi> of <hi>Objections</hi> to this ſame ſome may ſay.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Object.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Oh! here's a Table richly deckt, Oh here are diſhes ſtore,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Oh! is all this but one</hi> Small Mite, <hi>and from a</hi> Widow poor:</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Though here are many good Diſhes, they have not the right place,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Nor in good Order <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ſherd in, oh this doth ſpoile the Grace;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>For there are ſometimes Diſhes come, the which ſhould last be brought,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And this Courſe will not it admit, of this ſome will find fault,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Though we confeſs the meat be good, and on the Table ſtore,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>But Sauce here is not ſutable, to ſight it is but poor.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <pb n="45" facs="tcp:62159:23"/>
                  <head>Anſw.</head>
                  <l>My <hi>Anſwer</hi> this no<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> 
                     <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>nquet</hi> is, for them full <hi>Stomack</hi> have,</l>
                  <l>But <hi>bitter</hi> things for <hi>hungry Soules,</hi> which newly come from <hi>grave.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But yet in it ought ſweetneſs find, O this is all my aim,</l>
                  <l>To praiſe the goodneſs of our God, for his <hi>Love</hi> in the ſame.</l>
                  <l>And ſeeing meat is on the Board, if it be'nt rightly ſet,</l>
                  <l>Let others take the pains that can the Diſhes places <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap>it.</l>
                  <l>Now for my part when I did taſte any diſh that was good,</l>
                  <l>I preſently brought him to board, to others, for their food.</l>
                  <l>If in Feaſts they firſt <hi>beſt Wine bring,</hi> and after that that's worſt,</l>
                  <l>Yet Chriſt when he <hi>makes Water Wine,</hi> the laſt's as good as firſt.</l>
                  <l>So theſe <hi>Traditions</hi> we do not, in our minds much admire,</l>
                  <l>So hungry Souls with <hi>Righthouſneſs</hi> be fed, is our deſire.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Object.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Tautologies,</hi> O ſome may ſay, be here, I do them find,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which are Diſhes of one like meat, this doth not pleaſe the mind.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Anſw.</head>
                  <l>My <hi>Anſwer</hi> is, 'twas meat I lov'd, that I often did eat,</l>
                  <l>And ſo for't ſhould not be reprov'd, for giving of my meat,</l>
                  <l>This way <hi>Prophets</hi> and <hi>Apoſtles,</hi> did uſe, with <hi>Line</hi> on <hi>Line,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Thus putting Saints in remembrance by ſtirring their pure mine,</l>
                  <l>And that 'twas not grievous to them the ſame thing for to write,</l>
                  <l>Yea thoſe things which they did believe, and had thereof the ſight.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Object.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>But now again for to return, and wonder at this</hi> Mite,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Which is come forth in many words, this Title is <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 span">
                           <desc>〈…〉</desc>
                        </gap>ight.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Anſw.</head>
                  <l>When I at firſt my <hi>Mite</hi> had caſt into Gods <hi>Treaſury.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>The more I caſt the more I had, how could this <hi>Miracle</hi> be?</l>
                  <l>My <hi>Siſter</hi> of <hi>Sareptha</hi> was, alſo a <hi>Widow</hi> poor,</l>
                  <l>A little <hi>meal</hi> and <hi>oyl</hi> ſhe had, oh this was all her ſtore:</l>
                  <l>And this was but to ſerve one time, oh! <hi>Death</hi> it was ſo nigh,</l>
                  <l>And ſhe was gon to <hi>dreſs</hi> the ſame, to <hi>eat,</hi> and ſo to <hi>dye,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But when as that the <hi>Prophet</hi> came, and firſt deſir'd a <hi>Cake.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Her <hi>Faith</hi> was ſuch to give him ſome, forthwith the ſame did <hi>bake;</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>By <hi>giving of the Prophet ſo<gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1+ letters">
                           <desc>•…</desc>
                        </gap>e,</hi> her <hi>Meal</hi> it did not <hi>waſte,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Nor did the <hi>
                        <gap reason="illegible: blotted" extent="1 word">
                           <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
                        </gap>
                     </hi> of <hi>Oyl her fail,</hi> but <hi>increaſed</hi> as faſt.</l>
                  <l>For where <hi>Gods Word</hi> and <hi>Prophet</hi> is, there <hi>Mercies</hi> do not ceaſe,</l>
                  <l>And when the <hi>Mite</hi> is ſpent thereon, it doth hold forth <hi>encreaſe.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="46" facs="tcp:62159:24"/>
                  <l> For when my <hi>All</hi> is given up, <hi>God then is my All ſtill,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Then who can <hi>want</hi> that hath this <hi>All,</hi> tis He <hi>doth all things fill,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Then tis but <hi>giving unto God</hi> that <hi>ALL</hi> that we call <hi>our,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>In <hi>Faith,</hi> and he upon us will for it his <hi>Mercies</hi> pour.</l>
                  <l>King <hi>Solomon</hi> the ſame did ſee, the <hi>Scatterer</hi> did <hi>encreaſe.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And that which holdeth more thans meet,</hi> from <hi>Poverty</hi> did not ceaſe,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Yea he that watereth ſhall be watred himſelf alſo,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And that the Liberal</hi> ſhall be <hi>made fat</hi> as is a <hi>Doe.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So he <hi>that giveth of his ſtore,</hi> oh he ſhall not be <hi>poor,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>But <hi>Truth</hi> and <hi>Knowledge</hi> ſhall encreaſe, and fill him more and more.</l>
               </lg>
            </div>
            <div type="postscript">
               <head>POSTSCRIPT.</head>
               <lg>
                  <l>
                     <hi>POET</hi> I'm not nor <hi>Poets Son,</hi> at all that I ſhould <hi>rhime,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Howe're this ſame doth come to paſs, thus <hi>Eccho did my mind,</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Object.</head>
                  <l>
                     <hi>On this way ſome may evil think becauſe it is in Verſe,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And ſacred things they ſolid are, Meeter's not to rehearſe.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Anſw.</head>
                  <l>Though for this much may ſpoken be, yet this I ſay to thoſe,</l>
                  <l>That they that do not like the Verſe may read the ſame in Proſe.</l>
                  <l>And yet the <hi>Sacred ſolid Truth,</hi> will be the ſelf-ſame thing,</l>
                  <l>Tho <hi>Joyes</hi> ſurround did make me ſound <hi>Praiſes to Sions King.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And though I clap my hands for <hi>Joy,</hi> O who will angry be,</l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Raptures of Love doth my Soul move, Oh tis my Love, 'tis he!</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>That doth redeem poor Souls from Death, their Feet from falling to,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>And makes the Deſolate to ſing, Praiſes</hi> to him as due.</l>
                  <l>And why may no<gap reason="illegible: faint" extent="1+ letters">
                        <desc>•…</desc>
                     </gap> I ſing that <hi>New Song,</hi> as <hi>David</hi> formerly;</l>
                  <l>And as the <hi>Redeemed of God;</hi> that do <hi>Praiſe</hi> him thereby.</l>
                  <l>And ſhall not I in <hi>heart rejoyce,</hi> in God that is my <hi>ſtrength,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And is become <hi>Salvation</hi> unto me now at length.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Object.</head>
                  <l>But ſome may ſay, <hi>Thou crafty art in Verſe to bring this thing,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>That they that love not ſolid Truth, may hereby catch feeding.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>In this ſame way thinking there is meat fit for their minds then,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>They come to ſavour this your way, then you have catcht thoſe men.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <head>Anſw.</head>
                  <l>If that the World it be the Sea, and men the Fiſhes be,</l>
                  <l>And if this <hi>Bait</hi> doth catch them out, they'l <hi>praiſe</hi> the <hi>Bait,</hi> and he</l>
                  <l>Who is the <hi>Founder</hi> of this <hi>Love,</hi> them from this world to ſnatch,</l>
                  <l>By giving forth this mighty Power, that <hi>Fiſhes Fiſhes catch.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <pb n="47" facs="tcp:62159:24"/>
                  <l> In <hi>Heavens Net</hi> if men be <hi>caught;</hi> and from their <hi>element took,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>No cauſe they will have to repent, the <hi>Sea</hi> and <hi>World</hi> forſook.</l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>When th' <hi>Angler</hi> to the <hi>River</hi> comes, and doth him there ſit down</l>
                  <l>Minding the <hi>Water</hi> and the <hi>Fiſh,</hi> and <hi>Plumbing</hi> of the <hi>Ground,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>He then conſiders the <hi>Region,</hi> in which the <hi>Fiſh</hi> do <hi>ſwim,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Where <hi>high,</hi> or <hi>low,</hi> or <hi>middle way,</hi> he may put <hi>Bait</hi> therein.</l>
                  <l>So ſitteth ſtill expecting when <hi>ſome pleaſure</hi> he ſhall ſee,</l>
                  <l>How that his <hi>Bait</hi> doth pleaſe the <hi>Fiſh,</hi> that catched they may be,</l>
                  <l>And though Men may but nibble at this <hi>Bait</hi> it is <hi>good meat,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For it is made of <hi>Bread</hi> of <hi>Life,</hi> and fit for men to eat,</l>
                  <l>This was the guiſe that <hi>Paul</hi> did uſe, when he <hi>Corinthians</hi> took,</l>
                  <l>By meeting of them in their way, they ſwallowed <hi>Bait</hi> and <hi>Hook.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſo he to each <hi>Region went</hi> with this his <hi>Gospel</hi> clear,</l>
                  <l>Which is the <hi>mighty Power of God,</hi> and ſerveth every where;</l>
                  <l>From Chriſt when <hi>Peter had this Power</hi> his <hi>Net in Sea to caſt,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>What multitudes of <hi>Fiſh were caught,</hi> tho none all the <hi>Night paſt.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>Tis this <hi>Days Pawer</hi> makes <hi>Fiſh to come,</hi> it multitudes doth bring,</l>
                  <l>Without it <hi>Peter</hi> all night <hi>Fiſht,</hi> and yet he caught nothing</l>
                  <l>This is th'encreaſe that God doth give, with it when <hi>Paul doth plant,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>
                     <hi>Apollo's watering with the ſame refreſheth many a Saint.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <lg>
                  <l>Now for the preſent to conclude <hi>my Mite,</hi> my <hi>Cud</hi> thats good,</l>
                  <l>Whereby <hi>the clean Beaſts they were known, that fit were for mans food.</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>So bleſſed <hi>Mary ſhe laid up all Chriſts words in her heart,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And ſo ſhe <hi>chewd</hi> and <hi>ponderd them,</hi> leſt from her they ſhould ſtart,</l>
                  <l>So of my <hi>Cud</hi> I do give forth, <hi>that others it may chew,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For this may help to <hi>raiſe their own; Country people thus do,</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>And as it is with <hi>leaking Pumps,</hi> (<hi>looſe water,</hi> is the <hi>phraiſe</hi>)</l>
                  <l>To put <hi>water into their Heads, their own water to raiſe</hi>
                  </l>
                  <l>For if the <hi>dead</hi> it doth not <hi>raiſe,</hi> then is my writing vain,</l>
                  <l>However it doth witneſs for Gods <hi>Talent,</hi> and the <hi>Gain.</hi>
                  </l>
               </lg>
               <l>Melchiſedeck's <hi>our</hi> King <hi>and</hi> Friend,</l>
               <l>
                  <hi>His</hi> Prieſthood <hi>never will have END.</hi>
               </l>
               <closer>
                  <signed>E. Hincks.</signed>
               </closer>
               <trailer>END.</trailer>
            </div>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
